Chapter 65

Dark Witch

When Jake said he was good at zoning everything out when he focused on something, he meant he was really good at zoning everything out. Even the notifications he had gained during this time had gone unregistered. Luckily, he hadn’t pissed off this party by missing some crucial messages, as the Fallen King had honored his wish of not contacting him outside of emergencies—something the Unique Lifeform hadn’t found necessary.

Still… Jake could see why the Unique Lifeform was a bit unsatisfied when he finally checked his notifications.

Opening them up, the first thing he saw was that they had apparently gotten another bonus objective without him even noticing.

Bonus Objective Gained: Find a way to unlock the seal obscuring your path into the Dark Descent created by the Dark Witch leading toward the core of the planet.

Current Progress: Dark Descent unlocked (0/1)

So, this one confirmed the theory that the Dark Witch had indeed gone toward the core and even created a way to get down there. Of course, they likely had to also get rid of all three Living Seals before—

Bonus Objective Completed: Destroy all three Living Seals. 1000 Nevermore Points earned.

Right. They had also gotten that done, but hopefully, Jake could at least help with that seal on the—

Bonus Objective Completed: Dark Descent unlocked. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

Okay, Jake was beginning to realize he had indeed taken a little longer than he probably should have, but it seemed like things were going well!

Then again, there was still much to be done if one looked at the remaining bonus objectives they had gained during Jake’s minor mental absence.

Bonus Objective Gained: Discover the fate of the Dark Witch.

Current Progress: Dark Witch’s fate discovered (0/1)

Along with…

Bonus Objective Gained: Assist the New Beast Alliance in taking over the faction formerly known as the Beastfolk Alliance by helping to eliminate all enlightened beings remaining in their territory.

Current Progress: Enlightened Beings Remaining (2,093,778/9,421,400)

His party had clearly been up to quite a lot, with the Fallen King seemingly mid-genocide in the area formerly controlled by the Beastfolk Alliance.

“So… I apologize?” Jake sent. “Anyway, where are we? What is the status of things? I am especially interested in what is up with this New Beast Alliance.”

“The two other factions are entirely destroyed,” Dina explained. “Well, mostly destroyed. We found out that beasts are actually entirely unaffected by the Karmic Plague. It only works on those considered enlightened, so the Fallen King formed an alliance with the beasts there to wipe out all the enlightened, especially the Otherworlders.”

“Are you sure they are unaffected?” Jake asked, confused. “The Fallen King and Sylphie were both affected when we first got here, as far as I could feel.”

“Only in its inactive form,” Dina said. “The Karmic Plague cannot properly affect anyone not considered enlightened, so once it exits hibernation, it will just fizzle out. The Fallen King already confirmed the beasts that were part of the Beast Alliance were not affected.”

“Beasts that were all suppressed by the beastkin Otherworlders summoned here,” the Fallen King explained. “They did manage to reach some level of balance with the Otherworlders but never liked them. My arrival became their impetus to claim power and wipe out the enlightened. To reject such a purely beneficial objective seemed foolish, so we naturally accepted it. Should we fail, it is doubtful the Wyrmgod would penalize us, and should we succeed, it is merely bonus points.”

“And the Risen Kingdom?” Jake questioned.

“They had an unexpected case of heavy downpour,” the Sword Saint answered. “Sadly, the maniacs there, who sought to find a way to corrupt the Karmic Plague into something that would effectively mind control every enlightened being into desiring to be Risen, did not survive such unfortunate weather. As for a status on current events, the Fallen King and I are both on our way to Dina and Sylphie right now.”

“Got it,” Jake sent, sighing. Seemed like he had missed a lot. “How long was I unreachable?”

“Seven weeks and three days,” the Fallen King answered.

“See, honestly, from my point of view, this is as much on you as me for flying so slow you didn’t need me during all this time for anything,” Jake argued.

“That isn’t how things work,” the Sword Saint stated flatly.

“Fair enough, I zoned out a bit too hard… So, Sylphie, how are things?”

“Ree, ree, ree,” Sylphie explained, making Jake nod.

Seemed like they had done quite well, too. Found the old faction the Dark Witch had created and killed a bunch of beasts that had taken over the area, including a mini-boss monster that guarded the former capital. From there, they’d gathered a bunch of intel to learn a bit about the Dark Witch’s plan, including the location of the dig site she had created to reach the core.

Then they’d found the Dark Descent and discovered it had been sealed off by someone—likely the Dark Witch herself. They had then spent some time finding a way to unseal the barrier by researching what the Dark Witch had left behind, and were now making their way down the long, winding tunnels leading into the core of Tri-World—a task made quite a bit harder by the hordes of monsters in the way they had to fight through. Dina had at least left clues along the way, so once the Fallen King and Sword Saint arrived, they should be able to follow quite easily.

“So, considering even I can see the finale of this floor will play out down at or around the core, I guess you all figured it out too?” Jake surmised.

“Naturally,” the Fallen King stated. “And based on our estimates, I shall arrive at the entrance to the caverns in roughly a week, while the Sword Saint will be four days.”

“Aight.” Jake nodded to himself. “Want me to join Sylphie and Dina as soon as possible?”

“Was that not your original intention?” the Sword Saint asked. “Or do you need some more time to practice? Perhaps familiarize yourself with your new skill? I wouldn’t want to rush you.”

“No, I am fine with testing it out properly in real combat, so I will make my way to Sylphie,” Jake answered, not responding to the slight tone of sass in the old man’s voice.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked, just wanting to make sure.

He smiled lightly. “Yep, it shouldn’t take that long… but can you find a kind of open area? I get you are underground, but if there are any big caverns or anything, it would be great. Not entirely sure how accurate I will be.”

“Ree.”

Jake nodded and began to prepare himself, waiting for Sylphie to give the signal.

Now, one of the reasons his party had been fine with leaving Jake behind was because of what he was about to do.

When it came to long-distance travel, the best in their party was, surprisingly, the Sword Saint. Well, he was the best circumstantially. Through his profession, he could paint an area and “save” a moment in space that he could then travel to. This meant he was the fastest at returning somewhere he had been before… as long as you gave him a dozen or so hours to create a painting first.

Second-best was Jake. However, his means of travel were not as restricted as the Sword Saint’s, though his means also came with downsides. Accuracy was one of those downsides, especially considering Jake didn’t have a lot of practice with this method of travel, and the method wasn’t really designed as a long-distance travel skill anyway. Instead, it focused on distance, speed, and the ability to just get the hell away from where he currently was.

He was naturally talking about the special ability of his Wings of the Malefic Viper. An oft-ignored but incredibly useful aspect of the skill. Usually, Jake wouldn’t use it as a means of travel, but the circumstances of floor forty-one made it seem like a good idea. Plus, he could reduce many of the skill’s downsides by using a certain little hawk as a direction marker.

Jake and Sylphie still had a powerful connection through their Union Oath, allowing Jake to easily zone in on her. Over long distances, things like the Golden Mark or even his Hunter’s Mark sometimes got a bit fuzzy, but the Oath had no such problems—not surprising, considering its Primordial origin.

After a while, Jake got the signal from Sylphie and a slightly worried comment from Dina regarding whether he was sure things would work out as he planned.

“Relax,” Jake said, trying to calm her down as he got to work. “Even if things go slightly sideways, what’s the worst thing that can happen? That I get stuck in a wall or something? I’ll be fine.”

Wings sprang from his back as he also summoned scales all over his body. Taking a deep breath, he began to charge them with energy and activated the escape method of Wings of the Malefic Viper. Mist poured out and began to stick to his body as his entire form turned greenish.

The world seemed to distort as Jake flapped his wings once. Everything warped as Jake allowed his instinct to guide him. Sylphie’s location felt so close, yet so far away, as Jake flapped his wings several more times and went through a distorted world where even the concept of space was subverted and eroded.

Jake’s mana dropped by just over ten thousand points every single time he flapped his wings, his mana pool of 230,000 rapidly depleting. Luckily, it took less than ten seconds before Jake stopped the skill at the behest of his gut, telling him now was the time.

Unluckily, he had waited a fraction of a second too long to disengage the skill. The entire world turned dark, and Jake felt a deep pressure all over his body the second he faded back into reality. Jake kept his cool, having expected this to potentially happen.

Didn’t miss by too much, Jake thought, sighing in relief. Sylphie was only about a kilometer above him, and from a quick pulse, he saw that there was even a small cave on his path upwards.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked, having felt Jake nearby.

“Yeah, just a little stuck. Gotta take a second to—”

Before he was even done talking, he felt a thick vine wrap around his body and drag him upward through the path it had created. He still had to deal with rock and soil scraping him all the way up, but such was a minor sacrifice for quick travel.

“How did you miss and end up within the earth like that?” Dina asked the moment she dragged him out of the ground. “It was like you just appeared, yet I feel a distorted path…”

“I flew there, duh.” Jake smiled, having not really gone into detail about how Wings worked.

She just looked at him for a moment before looking back at the vine she had dragged him up. There were signs of rotting from the remnant poison left after the use of Wings. “Fine, a Legacy skill from the Malefic One. Are you ready to go, or did the skill take a lot out of you?”

Jake was down to just a bit above a quarter, but after popping a potion, he was all good to go. He wouldn’t be able to summon his Wings of the Malefic Viper for a few days, but that should be fine, considering he was underground. The slight feeling of weakness after using such an escape skill also wasn’t that big of a deal either, as Jake had joined them more as a guide than a fighter, and Sylphie and Dina were more than capable of defeating all the beasts on the way down.

From there, the trek towards the center of Tri-World continued. Sylphie and Dina had already gotten pretty damn deep by the time Jake arrived—nearly thirty percent of the way already—but that still meant there was a lot to go. Luckily for them, Jake was a good guide when leading them through the elaborate tunnel system created by the Dark Witch.

Rather than natural tunnels, it was clear these ones had been dug. Magical reinforcements could be found here and there, and waymarkers were placed at certain intervals, with there even being a few sealed-off rooms hidden away off to the side of the cavern at times.

However, it was also clear the tunnel had been heavily neglected. No one had been there for a few hundred years, so the beasts had taken over again. Most of them were worm-like beasts called Tunnelers—the same creatures the Caravan Guard Captain had warned them about. These Tunnelers came in many variants and sizes, and they could be threats if one was taken by surprise or got swarmed, especially in an environment that was so beneficial to them. Being stuck in a cavern surrounded by earth while fighting creatures using earth magic was always problematic.

Ultimately, these damn Tunnelers did little more than slow down their descent, especially when they decided that trying to collapse a part of the tunnel on them was a good idea. Even when mini-boss versions appeared, the three of them easily handled it. It was kind of monotonous, but at least the beasts they met got stronger as they descended.

They even began encountering other things deeper down. Elementals of the earth and lava variety, some insectoid monsters, and even a few fucking mushroom bastards that Jake called dibs on before utterly annihilating them. The only bad thing during all this was that using his new and improved Protean Arrow wasn’t ever necessary.

Days turned to weeks as they kept plunging deeper and deeper, and Jake hoped that they would soon face enemies worth fighting.

Sadly, before that could happen, the Sword Saint joined them, having been able to reach them a lot faster by following the path they’d created. With him there, the fights naturally only got easier. A few weeks later, the Fallen King also rejoined the party proper, bringing the entire gang back together for what would hopefully be the final trek of floor forty-one.

Picking up their pace now that they didn’t fear getting surrounded by the constantly lurking monsters, they rapidly made progress, and only about a month later, they finally reached their destination. Through a Pulse of Perception, Jake saw a trapdoor of sorts leading into a giant, expansive space. Rushing down, they soon made it to the trap door. He had kept the huge space below scouted with pulse throughout their approach, but only after they dismantled the pretty simplistic seal on the trap door and opened it could he truly appreciate the sight.

This was the first time any of them—even Dina—had seen the core of a planet. Jake stared at a giant, red, molten orb floating in the middle of the chamber, more than five kilometers across and absolutely pulsing with power and pure energy. Surprisingly, it only gave off a little bit of heat, despite looking like a miniature sun.

The cavern that housed this massive core was even more enormous. It was almost entirely spherical and about five hundred kilometers in diameter, no matter where one decided to measure it.

Jake and the others stared for a while… but Jake also felt like something was wrong when he regarded the orb floating there right in the middle. Looking closely, he saw what appeared to be small runes flashing on the orb for a few seconds at a time, and from within it, he got an incredibly intense response from some of his skills.

Sense of the Malefic Viper, along with Palate, were both practically going insane. Something was hidden within the core… No, it was merged with the core. It had become one with it. For a moment, Jake had hoped that maybe the core was just corrupted by some item… but no.

Tri-World was fucked; no two ways about it. The core itself was completely filled to the brim with the Karmic Plague, its intensity so great that Jake didn’t doubt the people involved in infecting the planet had been at least A-grade.

As Jake and the others stared at the core, there was movement somewhere down below. There, Jake saw a creature wandering. A hunched-over, hooded being mulled about, seemingly without any aim, and sometimes stared up at the core. Jake used Identify while still at an angle where she seemingly hadn’t spotted them.

[Dark Witch – lvl 300]

“Level 300—I think the theory of her being the strongest on the planet is entirely correct,” Jake communicated to his party.

“So, what is the plan?” the Sword Saint asked.

Before anyone could respond, a system message popped up in front of them.

Bonus Objective Completed: Dark Witch’s fate discovered. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

“I… I see a path…” the Dark Witch muttered. “Heart unsealed… There is… a path…”

“My gut is telling me a fight is unavoidable here,” Jake spoke through the mark.

“You can’t know that…” Dina said, unsure. Right then, another message popped up.

Bonus Objective Gained: The Dark Witch has been corrupted by the Karmic Plague. Her mind is lost, yet a part of her seems to still hold onto her sanity and original goal. Now choose her final fate and, through that choice, the fate of Tri-World.

Current Progress: Dark Witch killed (0/1) OR Dark Witch defeated (0/1)

A dark pulse of energy suddenly went through the massive cavern containing the core. The moment it passed through him, Jake felt the attention of the Dark Witch below lock onto him. Him, and the four others with him.

“NO! More plague bearers! No!” The Dark Witch’s screeching voice rang throughout the massive core room. “Infected… but, monster not… also… human not? He… No, no, risky, risky. Only one choice acceptable…”

Behind them, the trap door leading into the core room slammed shut, and a massive dark seal appeared on it. At the same time, the color scheme of the entire core room turned a shade darker as tens of thousands of black runes lit up all over the walls. The only area not covered in darkness was the red core at the center.

Jake threw Dina a look. “Told you.”

“I will save you! I will cure you! I will kill you!” During her mad screeching, the Dark Witch’s body erupted with energy down below.

Dina just sighed. “Restrain, not kill.”

“Sure thing.” Jake nodded, pulling out his bow. He had to admit, he was a bit excited about this opponent.

This was his first time fighting a witch, after all. Could be fun.

Chapter 66

A Witch's Plan

Jake could admit when he was wrong. Sometimes, at least. This was one of those times.

Witches aren’t fun to fight.

Dark tendrils lined the walls, all of them semi-ethereal; they sought not to physically attack people, but leave them with some odd dark affliction that wasn’t a curse but seemed a lot like a curse. This particular affliction did damage and fucked with your senses, throwing them for a loop. Jake could definitely feel the roots of the magic in the dark affinity, but outside of that, he had no idea what he was dealing with.

“Hexes, try to avoid them,” Dina warned after Sylphie was hit and proceeded to smash into a wall, unable to tell up from down. “They are difficult to dispel.”

Okay, so they were dealing with hexes. Great.

Jake had tried to claim the upper hand right off the bat when the fight began by activating Arcane Awakening at the stable 30%. The Sword Saint and Fallen King had also joined him, with Sylphie trying but getting hit by another few tendrils.

The first barrage of arrows released by Jake was blocked by a black disc of pure energy that popped into existence not close to the witch, but only five or so meters in front of Jake. He would’ve blown himself up, had he not reacted fast enough to make all the arrows stable.

It wasn’t like the old man or Fallen King did much better. Rainclouds began to condense all around the room, but dark magic instantly influenced them, and the rainclouds became clouds of black smoke that flew toward the swordsman and encircled him.

Out of all of them, the Fallen King had the greatest success when he released a golden wave of force that the Dark Witch seemingly couldn’t do much to influence. Yet the moment it was about to strike, the witch seemed to just disappear, leaving nothing more than a pile of black sludge behind that absorbed the Fallen King’s golden wave.

Within the first ten seconds, it was established this fight would be annoying, and in the following minute, it was made extremely clear it would be very annoying. They were caught within the domain of a witch—one she had spent more than a century in. And it showed, as their party found themselves bombarded by various forms of magic from all sides, ranging from simple black bolts to odd hexes that did nothing but try and mess with you in some way. The Sword Saint even ended up getting hit by one that just made everything smell like absolute shit.

However, it wasn’t all bad.

“She is running out of energy, or at least spells,” Dina said through their Golden Mark. “Look, the runes on the wall are fading with every second.”

“And her mind clearly isn’t all there,” the Sword Saint added.

Jake had to agree. The spellcasting was complicated due to its inherent nature, and yet it felt sloppy and clearly not performed by someone with a plan. Usually, the most annoying opponent was someone who could string attacks together and claim momentum. This Dark Witch just threw everything and the kitchen sink at them, hoping something would hit them in the head. What was kind of weird was how her focus obviously shifted away from Jake, Sylphie, and the Fallen King throughout the fight, with nearly all of her offensive magic directed toward the Sword Saint and Dina.

This did confuse them initially, but Jake soon realized why.

“You two are the only ones affected by the Karmic Plague.”

Sylphie and the Fallen King were considered monsters and thus immune, while Jake had Palate of the Malefic Viper, which he had already used to remove any semblance of the plague from his body.

“Great, good to know,” the Sword Saint grumbled as he found himself surrounded by odd, eye-shaped objects that didn’t look like they were doing anything except staring at him menacingly.

The old man sent out an omnidirectional cut, making everything warp around him as he pushed away the eyes… only to find several of them appearing again, this time covering his sword and robe, freaking him out a little. Dina cast some spell on him that made the eyes instantly disappear, but this only seemed to pull the attention to her.

Sylphie and the Fallen King tried to do something to the Dark Witch, but she was seemingly impossible to lock down. To make matters worse, the dark aura in the room wasn’t just there to limit visibility and enhance her own magic. Jake had activated Arcane Awakening at 30%, yet he felt himself dropping in power ever so slowly, and was now down to a level where it felt like the boost was only at 20%.

In other words, they were in a race to deplete the Dark Witch’s power before they themselves were depleted. The best way to deplete her seemed to be attacking repeatedly, but none of them had managed to land a blow yet. Jake had a plan, though.

“Next time she reappears, I will try to land a hit,” Jake said right after the Sword Saint shot out a beam of water, the Dark Witch once more turning herself into black sludge.

Jake had managed to place a Hunter’s Mark on her before she disappeared, but when she’d vanished, so had the Mark. It wasn’t gone, though… just scattered. He nocked an arrow and drew the string, holding back on doing anything and allowing Dina to protect him while waiting for the Dark Witch to appear. Not that she had to do much to protect him, considering the Dark Witch would rather attack the dryad over him.

A few seconds later, he felt the energy from the Hunter’s Mark begin to gather. Without any hesitation, he turned and shot a hastily charged Arcane Powershot toward where she was about to pop into existence. While the arrow was in flight, her form coalesced, and before she could turn into sludge again, Jake hit her with Gaze of the Apex Hunter.

It worked. Kind of. The Dark Witch was frozen for a moment, allowing the extremely fast arrow to strike her, and she only managed to turn herself into sludge again halfway through the following explosion. What did not go that well was what happened to Jake.

The moment he had used Gaze on the Dark Witch, something had gazed back into him. His vision entirely disappeared, blinding him. Next went every single one of his other senses, even his sense of touch and balance. Everything felt wrong, and if not for his sphere, he would have been entirely disoriented, as if stuck in a black space of emptiness, trapped within his own mind.

Fucking hell, he cursed internally, feeling more insulted than anything. Through his sphere, he saw pockets of energy gathering close to him, but before they could even fully appear, the dark aura clinging to Jake’s form was dispelled, and his eyes gave off a deep orange glow.

Dina hadn’t even had time to start casting something to dispel whatever had affected Jake before he overcame what he assumed was some kind of hex through the power of pure Perception. Jake’s feeling of indignance for her daring to attack his wonderful Perception would not go unpunished. He quickly nocked another arrow.

If she wanted to play hide and seek, Jake was gonna show her he was the best damn seeker around.

The next time she appeared, Jake instantly struck, hitting her once more. A few seconds later, Sylphie slammed into her after following Jake’s direction, with a massive golden beam hitting her at the next place of appearance. The Dark Witch didn’t seem to take much damage from individual strikes, but the many dark runes lining the wall did disappear at a far more rapid pace.

Meanwhile, Dina and the Sword Saint were having a less-than-pleasant time as weirder and weirder magic began to appear. At one point, Dina even had to struggle when Bobo accidentally shot a thorn into her stomach; his senses had somehow switched around, making him think he was shooting a thorn away from her and not into her.

The old man had it even worse, as he didn’t have a Bobo to defend him, forcing the Fallen King to step in a few times to avoid the swordsman taking a dangerous blow. His senses seemed entirely off, his attempts to parry inaccurate and not at all like him.

This annoying battle of perseverance continued, and Jake soon knew that holding back was not an option. Arcane Awakening activated at the offensive 50%, with his other party members also using their boosting skills to try and weather the storm of dark magic.

Throughout this all, Jake was also doing one more thing: creating an arrow.

Within his quiver, a Protean Arrow was being carefully constructed. Jake was approaching this with caution, condensing a very special arrow just for the Dark Witch. Killing her was not the objective, just weakening her, so Jake wanted to make a poison aimed to do just that. The internal layer would be with the usual concepts, even if his knowledge about the Dark Witch was pretty much nonexistent. When it came to the second layer, Jake would lace it with quite the dose of neurotoxins, making it a true knockout arrow.

All he would need was a bit of time, and his Protean Arrow should be able to—

“I got it,” the Fallen King spoke.

An explosion of light erupted from the Unique Lifeform as the outline of a crown appeared floating above him. In the very next moment, the crown shattered, sending a shockwave of pure golden energy through the entire core room.

The Dark Witch had just reappeared when the golden aura washed over her. The hood covering her hunched-over form was blown back, revealing her true form. She was some kind of scalekin, and her empty black eyes suddenly seemed to regain focus.

“What… Where…?” the voice of the Dark Witch echoed throughout the hall as Jake threw the Fallen King a look.

Damn asshole just had to take away Jake’s cool moment.

The Dark Witch below looked completely out of it, but the remaining runes covering the cave walls had all stopped glowing, and the dark aura making them all lose power was gone. Jake’s danger sense also told him there were no hidden threats.

“I didn’t know you could do that,” Dina said, sounding pretty exhausted from having dealt with the attacks from the Dark Witch but happy the Fallen King had succeeded.

“The effects of the Karmic Plague on her were soul-related in nature—is it not only natural I would find a solution, considering my station?” the Fallen King answered, sounding cocky as hell.

Which, to Jake, was code for the Fallen King not actually knowing he could do it either. He had just suddenly figured out a potential solution halfway through the fight and now wanted to flex on them like he had known all along.

While Jake was still grumbling about not being allowed to use his super-cool new arrow, they got a notification about completing a bonus objective.

Bonus Objective Completed: Dark Witch defeated. 1500 Nevermore Points earned.

Jake checked the message and was a bit surprised at getting 1500 Nevermore Points. The number felt both too small and too big. They had fought a level 300, true, but it wasn’t a true level 300 witch. It was more like they had fought the mostly passive defensive spells cast upon this domain before she went insane. Had they actually fought her for real… Yeah, that would have been a lot more annoying.

Speaking of the Dark Witch…

“You… You are Otherworlders?” she spoke as she looked up at them with confusion. The witch took a few moments to gather herself, then bowed. “I apologize; I lost myself. When I felt the Karmic Plague begin to take hold of my soul, I attempted to avoid it by warping my psyche and sealing away the influence… Obviously, that didn’t go well.”

Seeing as things had calmed down, Jake and company floated down toward where the witch was standing. She patiently waited as she cast some kind of magic on herself. Her body warped slightly as her crooked back straightened, allowing her to stand upright. Her flayed robe was also changed out for a newer one, which was when Jake noticed something else.

She didn’t have any real equipment on during the fight, either… Yeah, definitely not gonna try and fight a witch dozens of levels above me within her domain again, Jake told himself. Well, not anytime soon, anyway.

The Dark Witch observed them carefully as they floated down, her eyes especially on the Fallen King and Jake. “I greet the Unique Lifeform. From your aura, I suspect it was you who managed to awaken me from my stupor?”

“It was indeed,” he said, full of smugness. At least, Jake interpreted it that way.

“Then I must thank you,” she said, bowing toward the Unique Lifeform before turning to Jake. “But… you… Why are you unaffected by the Karmic Plague?”

Jake was a bit surprised she could feel whether he was infected or not… but then again, he knew he really shouldn’t be. The lady had spent a long-ass time trying to get rid of it, so being able to identify it wouldn’t be weird.

“I was affected,” Jake answered honestly. “I just got rid of it.”

She stared at him for a few seconds before frowning. “That… shouldn’t be possible. The origin of this Karmic Plague was an early S-grade. A C-grade should not have the ability to resist it unless… Are you in any way related to the Order of the Malefic Viper?”

Jake was once more taken aback at the question. Mainly because she knew about the Order of the Malefic Viper. Usually, these dungeon characters didn’t seem to know much about the outside world… but then again, she did also know that the Fallen King was a Unique Lifeform.

“I am a member of the Order, yes,” Jake said, deciding to answer truthfully.

“Were you sent here to deal with the Karmic Plague, too?”

“Wait, you are a member of the Order?”

She shook her head. “No, I am not. But the faction I belong to was hired by the Order to be on the lookout for instances of plagues still out there, and I got unlucky and ended up here when I flew too close to the sun with one of my divination attempts, triggering whatever ungodly teleportation the maniac who planted the Karmic Plague also placed on this planet.”

Jake nodded as Dina also stepped forward, asking with quite a bit of hope, “We heard you were working on some way to address the Karmic Plague but got stopped by the other factions… can you tell us more about that? Is it possible to save this planet?”

“The planet… Yes, it should be possible,” the Dark Witch said, nodding. “But the people on it… That is another story. Though I can see you already managed to get rid of some of those old bastards. Back then, they came to me and said they wanted to help me to get rid of it. I thought it was odd with the Karmic Plague and all, but I felt desperate. Halfway through the ritual they were supposed to help me with, they all suddenly turned on me. The backlash from the failed ritual weakened me significantly, and when they all attacked at once… I had to flee down here. I was unconscious for a while, but my passive defenses managed to keep them away. When I awoke, I found my methods were unusable due to the Living Seals placed on them, and my mind had already heavily deteriorated.”

Ah, there we go, Jake thought with relief. The Dark Witch was beginning to feel a bit too real, so it was nice to see she still had some pretty clearly scripted dialogue. Or maybe she just really liked to talk about her own background while giving out exposition.

“How do you plan on addressing the Karmic Plague?” Dina asked. “If it was truly placed by an S-grade…”

“Usually, I would agree, but I got lucky. Before I was sent here, my master had already given me an item and a method to address infected planets I came across. Those other bastards sealed it away, but now that the Living Seals are gone, it is usable once more.” The Dark Witch then held out both hands.

Energy gathered, and soon a stone only about twenty centimeters in diameter appeared, floating above her palms. Jake used Identify and was taken aback.

[Mimicry World Core (Unique)] – A mimicry of a true World Core, able to mirror another true World Core.

That… definitely seemed like a special item, and Jake already had a good idea of what the Dark Witch was about to say next.

“Using this Mimicry World Core, my original plan was to mirror the World Core you see before you and then transfer the Karmic Plague into it, away from the true core of this planet. I have researched the Karmic Plague, and it should be possible. I also discovered that this specific strain of the Karmic Plague does have a built-in failsafe: As long as the source—in this case, the energy within the core—is destroyed, a chain reaction will occur, wiping out anyone infected.”

Well, that sounds convenient, Jake thought, nodding.

“So… I ask of you… Will you assist me in this ritual?” she asked with hope in her voice, and an objective appeared.

Bonus Objective Gained: The Dark Witch has been awakened from her failed attempt to circumvent the influence of the Karmic Curse. She has asked you to help her in ridding Tri-World of the Karmic Plague once and for all through a ritual that will also slay all those infected if the Mimicry World Core is destroyed afterward.

Current Progress: Assist the Dark Witch in the ritual to cleanse Tri-World of the Karmic Plague.

Jake saw the objective and quickly exchanged glances with his party members. It was clear they all knew what they were doing now. And, hey, even if Jake didn’t get to use his cool new arrow, at least he would be able to do some ritual magic to get one over on the Fallen King.

He was a bit sad about missing out on a prime opportunity to do a planetary sacrificial ritual, but oh, well—he would probably get another shot at some point.

Chapter 67

Something Reckless

When it came to rituals, their group only really had two individuals who could be of any use. Dina and Jake both knew quite a bit about rituals and formations, while the other three were just sitting ducks incapable of assisting with anything of substance.

At least, not in the beginning. Jake and Dina helped the witch set up the initial parts of the ritual but soon hit an issue that they should honestly have seen coming.

“Many of the ingredients I wanted to use are no longer capable of supporting the ritual… We will need some replacements,” the Dark Witch said with a deep frown. “Would it be possible for some of you to perhaps acquire them?”

That’s right—there were fetch-quests. That at least gave the Fallen King, Sword Saint, and Sylphie something to do while Jake and Dina worked on the ritual circle with the Dark Witch. Jake had feared this would add a lot of time to this final part of floor forty-one, given the long trek the three of them would have to go on for each item, but luckily the Dark Witch had a way to alleviate that.

While space magic was distorted on the planet, she had found a way to faintly tap into this concept and set up a few teleportation points across the planet, all of them underground. Some had been broken with time, but most were still functional. The only bad thing about these teleportation points was that they were one-way only. So the three of them would have to make their own way back.

This was a problem for all of them… except for a certain old man who got to painting straight away. Considering he would have the easiest time getting back, Sylphie and the Fallen King were tasked with retrieving the items closest to the entrance of the Dark Descent, while the old man would go for everything else. All in all, the Dark Witch needed five items from powerful mini-boss monsters spread across the planet. A totally random number of items, and not at all one corresponding to the number of people usually in a Nevermore party, Jake was sure.

With everything hard at work, time passed rapidly. Jake and Dina managed to get in plenty of conversation with the Dark Witch during this time and learned a lot about the history of Tri-World, as well as all the knowledge she had about Karmic Plagues. What was most interesting was just how much she knew, especially when it came to stories about how plagues had done harm to the multiverse.

She was practically a living lexicon of horror stories brought on by plagues, making it very clear how bad they were, and several times she mentioned how plagues were the closest thing to being outlawed that anything could be in a lawless multiverse. How if one of them decided to ever try and create a plague, they would be hunted down and killed. That last part was aimed solely at Jake for some reason, not giving Dina enough credit. She could totally make a plague if she put her mind to it.

During this ritual construction process, Dina and Jake discussed how they had to keep an eye out for anything hidden within the massive magic circle they were making. Something that would allow the Dark Witch to do something they had not discussed or planned on.

Perhaps they were being paranoid, but getting double-crossed was kind of the expected outcome. Jake wouldn’t be surprised if she somehow changed the ritual halfway through to absorb the plague for power or maybe spread it far and wide, as she—in a massive plot twist—had actually been entirely corrupted and was doing all this to assist the Karmic Plague.

But nothing seemed to be wrong with the ritual to either of them, no matter how far they got in the process, and after a bit over two months, the ritual circle was completed. The Sword Saint had made three trips during this time, teleporting back through his weird painting magic, with the Fallen King and Sylphie fetching one item each.

With everything ready, Jake was still hesitant. Because there was one part of this entire thing they hadn’t quite addressed.

If everything went as planned, the Karmic Plague would be destroyed. Destroying it would kill anyone infected with said plague. Both the Sword Saint and Dina would be fine, as they weren’t actually infected yet due to the fifty-year incubation period, but… the Dark Witch would not. This meant that while Jake didn’t get to do a sacrificial ritual for a planet… he had been helping a witch construct a ritual for her own suicide.

He and the other four weren’t going to leave this unmentioned, as it was the biggest cause of their suspicion the Dark Witch would try to pull something. However, if she was honestly willing to sacrifice herself…

“We are done,” the Dark Witch said, smiling happily upon seeing the ritual circle Jake and Dina had helped make.

It was directly below the core, but once the ritual began, the Karmic Plague from within the World Core would detect the Mimicry World Core and, due to its design, be unable to resist infecting what it thought was another planet. Once it transferred just a little energy, the ritual would allow the rest to be dragged into the Mimicry World Core and thus dispel the World Core of Tri-World entirely. All of this was naturally only possible due to the Mimicry World Core, which was honestly overpowered in Jake’s eyes and clearly an item designed for something just like this.

“We are done, indeed.” Jake nodded as he studied the circle before looking at the witch directly. “I am not going to beat around the bush. Based on your own words and what we designed this ritual to do, if we successfully pull this off, you will die in the process.”

The Dark Witch looked at Jake and the others with a smile. “I know. Don’t get me wrong—I am not a fan of dying, but I knew from the very beginning this was a risk I would be running when I walked this Path. Even now, I feel the influence of the Karmic Plague gnawing at me. I can suppress it for now, but in just a few years, I will be back to being the mindless monster you fought when you first encountered me. Death is preferable to that. Going out taking this damn plague with me isn’t the worst death, at least. I do wish you five luck in getting off the planet, though. While I have no future, it is not the same for you all.”

Her words seemed sincere, at least to Jake. He knew he, at times, messed up, but he still felt like he could get a read on people’s vibes, and the Dark Witch gave off the vibe of someone who truly would do anything to get rid of the Karmic Plague. That small speech only reaffirmed his thoughts and made him feel a bit bad about being so suspicious.

“When immortality is not on the table, a good death is the best end for a well-lived life,” the Sword Saint said, nodding respectfully.

Dina clearly didn’t like it but still nodded solemnly. Jake didn’t know if this entire floor was about teaching them moral lessons, but he didn’t like that the only “right” decision was one where not everyone could be saved.

“Let us not delay more than necessary,” the Dark Witch said in a resolute voice. “While my mind is still mine, I want to finish this once and for all.”

All that was left was to respect her wish, and thus they got to work. All six of them were necessary for the ritual, though the Sword Saint, Fallen King, and Sylphie would only serve as energy sources and stabilizing elements, while the Dark Witch was the primary controller. Jake and Dina would directly support her, which would help the ritual to proceed faster. Usually, it would take about a week, but with Jake and Dina there to help, the Dark Witch estimated no more than a single day would be needed, as she wouldn’t require any rest periods.

With everyone in place, the ritual began. Right below the true World Core floated the Mimicry World Core, ready to mirror the giant, molten orb above and become the new host for the source of the Karmic Plague. Jake still had to admit he wasn’t entirely clear on how the ritual would proceed; he just knew he would be supporting the Dark Witch in whatever she did.

Runes covering the entire chamber lit up—not with the usual, darkish light, but a deep red. Energy instantly began filling the core room, much of it provided by their party of five, along with all the items prepared by the Dark Witch and recovered by the Fallen King, Sylphie, and Sword Saint.

These runes then began to send light toward the middle point right between the true World Core and the Mimicry floating many kilometers below it. Over the next many hours, a large, flat surface was summoned, resembling an odd black-and-red mirror that reflected both the Mimicry Core and true World Core.

At the twenty-six-hour mark, Jake felt the ritual approach completion. Two World Cores were reflected in the mirror, overlapping perfectly. The Dark Witch sent them all a signal as they prepared for the final part. With a push of power, the entire chamber began rumbling.

For a moment, Jake saw the true World Core flicker out of existence, replaced by the Mimicry Core, only for the real one to return instantly. Two realities were overlapping, both true and false at the same time, until suddenly, the mirror they had summoned shattered. All the runes across the room broke at the exact same time as the Dark Witch fell to her knees, exhausted.

Without even seeing the notification, Jake knew they had succeeded.

Bonus Objective Completed: Assist the Dark Witch in the ritual to cleanse Tri-World of the Karmic Plague. 2500 Nevermore Points earned.

Jake checked the notification and smiled a bit at their success. He threw his gaze toward the Mimicry World Core and nodded as he read its updated description.

[Mimicry World Core (Unique)] – A mimicry of a true World Core, able to mirror another true World Core. A mimicry of the Tri-World’s core has been created from this item, and the source of a powerful Karmic Plague now resides within. This item has a built-in self-destruction sequence that can be activated at any time, utterly destroying the core.

The ritual was complete and had gone off without a hitch, just as they had planned. There was no deceit, no double-crossing. The Dark Witch didn’t even make a move for the Mimicry World Core that now had the Karmic Plague in it. She hadn’t done one shady thing throughout, which weirdly enough felt… weird. To see someone—especially someone called the Dark Witch—be so honest and truthful throughout, making a selfless sacrifice…

It rubbed Jake the wrong way about how this was all supposed to go down. He didn’t like this ending.

No one had to say anything as their group gathered right in front of the floating Mimicry Core. The Dark Witch was the last one to arrive. She looked entirely spent, though she had a proud smile on her lips.

“We did it,” she said in a melancholic voice. “Now all we have to do is destroy the core, and this will be over… Don’t worry—the self-destruction is not an explosion, but a built-in implosion of sorts, more or less just erasing the entire core from existence. It was made for cases like this, after all. All that one needs to do in order to activate this feature is infuse energy into the formation on it…”

Jake sensed her hesitation, as she didn’t make a move to do what she had just said was oh so simple. Simply doing an action you knew would be the end of you wasn’t easy. That one moment was enough hesitation for Jake to sigh.

“Ah, fuck it,” he muttered as he looked at his party. “Am I allowed to be a little reckless here?”

“This is a dungeon; nothing done here truly matters,” the Fallen King said. “But I believe that goes both ways… If there is a time to embrace recklessness, perhaps now is the time. Fine, go ahead—perhaps there will even be bonus points for such a thing—but do not end your own existence for a stupid sense of vanity.” Clearly, he understood Jake wanted to do something potentially moronic.

The Sword Saint just shrugged, with Dina looking confused about what Jake planned to do. Sylphie didn’t seem to care overly much either way.

“Well, then,” Jake said as he looked at the Dark Witch. “Wanna take a risk and see if we can get that Karmic Plague out of you?”

She stared at Jake for a moment before shaking her head. “While the thought is appreciated, I am well aware of the nature of this Karmic Plague. It has merged with me already, and my fate is sealed. Nothing short of a god could change that outcome.”

“It isn’t that bleak,” Jake said. “The Karmic Plague is infecting you, yes, but differently than others. You managed to almost segment it away from the most vital parts of your soul, so while getting rid of it won’t be easy, it isn’t impossible either.”

The Dark Witch just sighed again. “Once more, I am aware. It was done in an attempt to save myself, but it didn’t work properly. The Karmic Plague is designed to destroy me if the source is destroyed, and my feeble attempts will do nothing to change that.”

“If you are so confident you are going to die, just let me give it a shot.” Jake shrugged. “The worst outcome is what you expect anyway.”

“The worst outcome is you ending up also infected or sharing my fate,” she said sternly.

“I’ll be fine,” Jake said, waving her off.

He then turned toward the Mimicry World Core and opened his mouth. Palate of the Malefic Viper activated as Jake used the skill in a fashion he hadn’t for a while: He quickly took out the item he had in his Palate—one of the treasures given by the Risen during his ceremony—and prepared to consume the fake World Core.

“What are you doing!?” the Dark Witch yelled as the core shrank and flew into Jake’s mouth. “That core isn’t something a C-grade can suppress! The innate will of the world is mirrored, too, and… and…”

Jake stood there, rubbing his stomach and feeling the tremors of energy go through his body as the rowdy fake World Core complained. At least, it did for a moment before Jake clamped down on it hard. One had to remember that the “stomach” of Palate was within his soul… and once it was in there, Jake felt the plague resonate with something else in there and calm down.

Within his Soulspace, the drop of blood from the Malefic Viper pulsed with energy only once, suppressing the corrupted World Core entirely before going silent once more. This hadn’t even been a necessary part of Jake’s plan, but it was a nice surprise. What was even more of a nice surprise was what had come with that pulse of energy from the drop of blood. Knowledge of plagues had flooded his head, courtesy of Sagacity, saving him a lot of the time he would’ve needed to absorb it with Palate.

The Dark Witch just stood there, staring at Jake for a few moments. “Who the hell are you?”

“Someone with a plan.” Jake smiled as he turned and looked at the Sword Saint. “Could you give me a hand?”

“What do you need me to do?” the old man asked.

“When I give the signal, could you be nice and stab me in the head with that Glimpse of Spring: Erosion thing?”

Chapter 68

Fate Decided

“You know we can’t allow him to actually bring that Mimicry World Core out of that floor, right?” the Wyrmgod questioned the Malefic Viper.

“Does seem kind of counterproductive if he decides to reintroduce a Karmic Plague that was wiped out a long time ago back into the multiverse,” Minaga said, nodding in agreement.

“Relax—he isn’t gonna actually bring it out,” the Viper said, waving them off. “He is just going to eat it and consume all its knowledge of how to make plagues.”

“And… that’s a good outcome?” Minaga said in a deadpan tone. “Totally seems like a good idea to teach him about them… especially considering his track record of always making well-thought-out decisions.”

“Come on… Would he really be my Chosen if he didn’t at least know how to create a plague?” The Viper smiled. “Not saying he should make one, but nothing wrong with learning how to.”

“I am confident nearly every other faction in existence would disagree with that assessment,” the Wyrmgod said with a sigh.

“And I am confident at least half of those have a rule written somewhere that one of the reasons they shouldn’t fuck with me is out of fear I will throw a plague at them,” Vilastromoz said, shaking his head.

“Hm,” the Wyrmgod said after thinking for a while. “I will reclaim the World Core if he brings it out, but should he consume it or sufficiently alter it, I shall allow him to leave with it as long as there is no chance of reintroducing the plague.”

“Sounds fair enough,” Vilas said, shrugging.

“Also, to be fair, I think most factions wouldn’t fuck with the Malefic Viper even without the plagues,” Minaga said. “And I do guess there is value in knowing how to make one, as there are some very interesting concepts at play. Speaking of which, seeing as you are the expert here… Would it be possible to make a plague that wipes out Bloodlines that allow those possessing them to ruin any and all interesting labyrinth experiences? Asking for a friend.”

Just to clarify, Jake wasn’t planning some over-the-top double suicide or anything when he asked the old man to stab him. He just knew that what he was about to do wouldn’t be something he had confidence in pulling off under normal circumstances, so he decided to indulge in some clever use of system mechanics.

“You want me to trigger that defensive skill of yours that activates from a lethal blow?” the Sword Saint questioned, having quickly picked up on what he was getting at.

“Ah, that one.” The Fallen King nodded in understanding, having also experienced that one himself.

“Exactly.” Jake smiled. “And I reckoned that Erosion thing is the best skill to use, as it seems pretty easy to dodge compared to the slash, considering it is just one line of water. True, using the Transcendent skill may be me overestimating my durability, but I want to ensure the system will consider it a lethal blow.”

The Sword Saint considered for a moment before nodding. “Fair enough.”

Jake thanked him and turned to his three other party members. “Better make some distance to not get hit by anything. Ah, but Dina, probably stay close. Someone might need healing. On second thought, someone will definitely need healing.”

“What exactly are you planning on doing!?” the Dark Witch butted in rudely. “And what exactly did you do with the Mimicry World Core? It needs to be destroyed, or all of this is in vain… Wait, do you plan on keeping it? If that is the case, I will—”

“Relax, jeez,” Jake said, waving her off. “Trying to figure out a way to destroy the Karmic Plague without you dying in the process.”

“I… I already told you I am fine with my fate,” the Dark Witch said dismissively. “And unless you can call down a god, do you honestly think you or anyone else here can do anything?”

“Eh, I tend to be overconfident and reckless, yet I still turn out to be correct and have things work out for me in the end. And my gut’s telling me I can pull this off.”

“Trusting your gut? Don’t be ludicrous. If the Karmic Plague is unleashed within you, death is the only outcome.”

“Again, show some trust here. I also know quite a bit about plagues and even Karmic Plagues. At least let me give it a shot. Worst-case scenario, you die; best-case, you survive. Doing nothing is literally the same outcome as your worst-case scenario, so why the hesitation?”

“Because if something goes wrong, the Karmic Plague may not be destroyed. I—”

“This entire argument is getting circular and is wasting everyone’s time,” the Fallen King said in an annoyed tone. “Jake here is the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, so you should show some trust. If any C-grade can rid you of the Karmic Plague, it’s him.”

The Dark Witch was about to protest, but when the Unique Lifeform mentioned Jake was the Chosen, the lizard woman’s eyes opened wide. “I… I didn’t… I apologize for my—”

“So you’re on board?” Jake asked. He was a bit annoyed at the Fallen King spilling the beans like that, but things were getting tedious.

“I… Yes. I shall trust you, Chosen of the Malefic One.” The Dark Witch nodded resolutely, her voice slightly cracking.

Jake even saw a hint of hope in her eyes, which only reinvigorated his desire to pull this off. Deep inside, he knew it didn’t really matter, as they were in a dungeon and all… but he still wanted to do it.

“Great,” he said, smiling. “Now, here is my plan. While in physical contact with you, I will break the World Core inside of my stomach right as the Sword Saint hits me with a lethal blow. This will make time slow down for me as the Karmic Plague is destroyed, at which point I will manipulate the karmic energy going from within my stomach into you. Before this, I will infuse the plague within you with a toxin that will react with this karmic energy to only destroy the Karmic Plague along with the part of your soul you isolated together with it. This is still destroying the Karmic Plague, but it is more like cutting out an infected tumor before it gets a signal to spread the cancer to your bloodstream.”

“I am unsure what you mean with that final analogy, but I believe I understand what you mean. Will I need to do anything?”

“Don’t fight back, and focus on protecting your own soul,” Jake said. “It may get hairy, and it will definitely be a thoroughly unpleasant experience.”

She nodded, and Jake motioned for her to sit down as he looked at the Sword Saint. “I will need to set up some stuff before I begin, so it may take a bit before I need you to try and kill me.”

“Happy to try and stab you through the head any day.” The Sword Saint smiled and stood to the side of Jake, making sure his stab wouldn’t also hit the Dark Witch.

Jake sat down with his legs crossed as the Dark Witch sat in front of him. He put both his hands on her back and subtly activated Touch of the Malefic Viper, pouring in a tiny bit of poison as he scanned her body through Sense.

With her not resisting at all, even suppressing her natural vital energy, Jake quickly found the infected portion of her Soulshape. Her case was by far the best of anyone Jake had seen, but she was still in a precarious situation. Usually, the Karmic Plague would inhabit the entire soul, but the witch had managed to isolate it to somewhere around her stomach region. At least, most of it. Small slithers also hit other areas. Removing it would lead to some serious damage… but likely survivable.

With intense focus, Jake did two things at once. First, he pumped more poison into the witch using Touch as he “infected” the plague. This was to offer him some influence over it as he more or less tried to usurp control over the Karmic Plague. This was sadly also where his lack of power came in.

The reason he couldn’t just destroy the Karmic Plague on his own this way was due to the innate difference in level between Jake and the creator. Had Jake been A-grade, he would’ve been confident in being able to cure her entirely without having to take any major risks or even needing something like the World Core. However, as things were, all he could do was try and nudge the destruction process in a favorable direction. Something that should be enough, if his second objective went well…

He needed to influence the Mimicry World Core within his stomach, which he couldn’t really do currently. Of course, Jake already knew how he wanted to do this: through Touch of the Malefic Viper. His problem was that the only skill his Palate allowed him to use on a swallowed item was Cultivate Toxin, a shitty common-rarity skill.

But… for the longest time, Jake had known that shitty common-rarity skill wasn’t really necessary. He never used it. Instead, he used Touch of the Malefic Viper for most things. So, the question was… why even keep them separate? The answer was even more obvious. He wouldn’t. And he believed that if Cultivate Toxin became part of Touch of the Malefic Viper, then Palate would allow him to use Touch of the Malefic Viper on any item swallowed.

Jake needed to do little more than will for a fusion as he tried to influence the swallowed World Core. It barely took any effort on his part, almost as if the system had been waiting for him to stop being a moron and just get it done, and shortly after he began, a notification popped up.

*Skill Fusion Detected*:

[Cultivate Toxin (Common)] + [Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] --> [Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] (Rarity Unchanged)

Jake chose not to check out the updated description right away, as he knew it worked the way he wanted it to. He didn’t dwell on the unchanged rarity either, or the fact that he felt like he had just gotten a lot more Intelligence out of nowhere. Instead, he focused on Palate and the Mimicry World Core.

Instantly, he felt Touch activate on the Mimicry World Core, proving he had been correct. He looked within his Soulspace, observing the “stomach” of Palate and the core pulsing within as he slowly influenced it. It was naught but a slight nudge, and he felt the Karmic Plague fight back at every step.

Focusing on the core thoroughly, he put a lot of pressure on it and exerted as much control as he could. With his mind split, it was difficult, but Jake refused to back down. He knew that truly changing anything wasn’t going to happen, but as long as he could slightly nudge the plague to act differently when it encountered the other influenced plague energy within the Dark Witch, it should be enough. With a deep breath, he moved on to the next stage once he felt that trying to prime the core more wasn’t gonna happen.

You got this, he assured himself. The next part was where everything would be decided. Jake began to feel slight doubt about his plan as he slowly absorbed knowledge related to the Mimicry World Core, becoming aware that things weren’t entirely as he had hoped.

It was true that destroying the core could be done by activating the formation on it. It was also true it would just collapse without exploding and harming anything around it. The problem was that Jake had decided to eat it… and imploding it within his Soulspace was not something it was designed to do. In fact, he couldn’t even activate it.

So Jake decided that rather than using the built-in destruction formation, he would alter the formation on the core himself and change it from a harmless explosion to something a bit more destructive. This did still mean one thing, though: Jake would have to bear the brunt of effectively having a World Core explode within his own Soulshape.

“Be ready,” Jake communicated to the Sword Saint, and the old man got in position, sword raised and all.

He was worried about handling the fallout of an exploding core. Luckily for him, it was going to happen within his Soulspace, and as long as the resulting explosion was something he understood, he was confident in handling it. Well, having a part of him handle it, anyway. The amount of energy that would be released was substantial, but Jake had an even more substantial and powerful source of pure energy he could make use of to suppress it.

Within his Soulspace, a version of Jake covered entirely in a black, shadowy aura appeared right in front of the space that occupied the stomach of Palate. It looked like a massive orb of glass with the World Core floating in the middle, yet the shadow simply stepped through this glass and entered the bubble. This version of Jake then pulled back his arm, and a katar appeared on its hand.

“Now.”

The same moment he told the Sword Saint to attack, his Eternal Shadow stabbed the katar into the World Core, triggering its destruction.

Right as the katar pierced the core, Jake also heard the rumbling sound of Words as Power as his danger sense exploded, and a thin beam of water shot straight for his head. Both things happened within the same fraction of a second. The destruction of the core slowed down within his Soulshape, the concept of time momentarily seized.

And seize the moment he did. Jake barely registered the notification he got upon the destruction of the core as a shockwave of ethereal energy pulsed out from within his body, slowly spreading from the confines of his Soulshape.

[Palate of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] --> [Palate of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] (Rarity Unchanged)

Jake ignored this one, too, as he focused on the task at hand. An invisible aura he could only sense through his sphere moved out of him rapidly, even with Moment active. It washed over the Dark Witch, and instantly the Karmic Plague went haywire—or at least, it tried to.

It tried to spread and destroy to take the Dark Witch with it, but Jake controlled it. Barely. The lizard woman’s body was ravaged internally, several parts of her literally rotting away almost instantly. Jake barely had time to react to the function of the early S-grade Karmic Plague that told it to spread and stop it from infecting her entire soul at once. Emphasis on barely.

Whipping his head back, time resumed, and Jake felt a tinge of pain as his nose was cut off, but it was nothing compared to the screech that came from the Dark Witch. Half of her stomach had rotted away, along with one of her arms and several of her internal channels. Black spots of pure rot covered her body as Dina slammed her staff down, a green veil of energy covering both Jake and the Dark Witch.

Jake also quickly took out a healing potion and practically forced it down the throat of the Dark Witch, keeping a hand on her to handle any fallout from the Karmic Plague that may have lingered. However, it seemed like the entire Karmic Plague had just self-destructed, consuming any part of the body and soul it had been a part of, leaving the Dark Witch with severe soul and physical damage. But… it was nothing that wouldn’t heal with time.

As several seconds passed, all that was heard in the core room was the deep hum of the true World Core and the heaving, pained breaths of the Dark Witch. Dina was focusing as much as she could on healing, while Jake just kept staring at the Dark Witch, Sense of the Malefic Viper on full alert. The Fallen King even joined in by casting a soft golden light upon the Dark Witch, lessening her pain, from the looks of it.

Seconds kept ticking by, but no matter how much Jake searched, he couldn’t find a single trace of the Karmic Plague anywhere. Not even within any of his party members.

They had succeeded… and the Karmic Plague was gone.

The notification that came a few seconds later nearly made Jake laugh, as he had to admit he had forgotten about it.

Bonus Objective Completed: New Beast Alliance assisted with eliminating all Enlightened Beings in their territory. 1000 Nevermore Points earned.

He still smiled, as the notification had pretty much served as confirmation that the chain reaction caused by the Karmic Plague had indeed led to a mass extinction of all the enlightened on the planet. An odd thing to celebrate, but something worth celebrating, nevertheless.

“Are you okay?” the Sword Saint asked.

Jake was about to respond that the Dark Witch should be fine… but then he noticed the old man was staring at him.

Jake took a quick scan of himself and didn’t notice much out of the ordinary. At least, not outwardly. Looking inside his Soulspace, things were a bit messier. The stomach space created by Palate was lined with cracks, with intense curse energy lingering all over due to Jake being forced to deploy Eternal Hunger to suppress the energy backlash and avoid damaging himself.

What’s more… the stomach was still filled with energy. It looked like an inferno was sealed within, trying to break out but luckily restrained by the curse energy, along with what was left of the stomach’s structural integrity. Jake was worried about the energy until he noticed it depleting at a noticeable pace. Some of it did leak through the cracks of the stomach, only to be instantly consumed by the curse energy.

Seems like Eternal Hunger is having quite a feast… but it’s gonna take a while to heal Palate’s stomach space, he concluded as he finally returned his attention to the real world and smiled. “I’m fine. Honestly, better than I thought I would be.”

What was more important was the woman who was rapidly healing in front of him. The rotting flesh had slowly been removed or renewed, and while she still looked like shit, she was alive.

“I… I still live…” she muttered in a hoarse voice as she stared at the ceiling of the core room. Tears welled up in her eyes as she began to sob. “I live… How… I didn’t think…”

Jake just smiled, not saying anything as he allowed Dina to keep doing her work.

Not far away, right below the true World Core, a gate had already popped into existence, making it clear they had passed the floor. The fate of Tri-World had been decided. However, Jake wasn’t in that much of a rush, and neither were the others. For now, they just savored the moment before it was time to move on.

Chapter 69

Rewarding Good Behavior

Their party of five only ended up staying on the floor for an hour or so more while Dina finished healing the Dark Witch as much as she could. Some of the soul damage would have to heal on its own, but the scalekin was more than elated at just having survived.

“I don’t know how I can possibly thank you,” the Dark Witch said, bowing, as they stood in front of the teleporter that would transport them off the floor. “I hope you find fortune on your Path, and if I can ever repay this favor, I will do so.”

It was a bit melancholic, hearing her make promises of the future when the five of them knew such promises could never be fulfilled. Making her leave the dungeon with them also wasn’t an option. Chances were that even if the Dark Witch had ever been a true person, she was long dead in the real world, and if she still lived, it was because she had reached godhood… in which case this dungeon image also wouldn’t be able to leave. Not that any of that even mattered, as Nevermore didn’t allow the attendees to bring anyone from the dungeon out of it.

“Take care of yourself,” Jake said, “and keep fighting the good fight. The Lord Protector of the Enlightened Republic had some documents related to creating a way to teleport off the planet that may be able to help you leave, if that is what you want. There is a lab hidden beneath the destroyed capital.”

She nodded with gratitude as Jake and company walked through the gateway. It was odd how the Dark Witch seemed to know what the gateway was… but not truly. She knew it could take them off the floor—or planet—but not where it led or why she couldn’t enter it herself. Just that she couldn’t.

Appearing in the in-between room, Jake sighed loudly. Not because of the pretty damn boring room they appeared in, which really paled in comparison to the cozy lounges Minaga’s Labyrinth had, but because of the floor they had just done.

“Disconnecting these dungeon layers and the real world is difficult when the people become too real,” the Sword Saint muttered. “I will not lie; I find the floors where they seem more like pre-programmed characters preferable to this. Makes it all more straightforward.”

Jake nodded. “Yeah.”

“Having some experience with her fate myself, being a boss in a tutorial, I believe I have some unique insights,” the Fallen King said. “Even if the dungeon we experience is something we know isn’t truly real, to the individuals living there, it is their only reality. To the Dark Witch, she was just a member of some organization who had arrived to help cure it of the plague. From her perspective, she was truly saved. Ultimately, even saving a ‘true’ being in the multiverse is a mostly useless task, as they are but one soul in an infinite sea of lives, living in an endless timespan where their paltry mortal existences matter not. So act according to what you judge best, be it in a dungeon or in the true world. In the grand scheme, neither truly matters, and consciously writing off beings as unreal is an easy path to apathy. It is a path all gods eventually find themselves walking down… for is the life of a mortal which will end in the blink of an eye truly more real than the life of a being in a dungeon that only exists when you are in there? Both are but momentary blips on the tapestry of infinity that is their lives.” Oddly philosophical words for the Unique Lifeform, and though it definitely seemed like he had some unresolved thoughts from being in a system event… he also had some good points.

“I think what we did was good,” Dina said with a smile. “And being true to ourselves even in a situation where the stakes are low is only proof of being a strong character.”

“Ree,” Sylphie added wisely.

Jake just nodded, and before anyone else could say anything, they were hit with some long-awaited system messages.

Forty-first floor completed. 4100 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Destroy the Karmic Plague from Tri-World entirely using the ritual in partnership with the Dark Witch, curing the planet while still giving it a path to recovery. 2000 Nevermore Points earned.

Reading over the floor completion and achievement, Jake nodded. The 4100 had been expected, with the rule change of every floor giving more base points, but the achievement felt a little low, only giving 2000 extra for choosing what was effectively the hardest way of completing the floor. Then again, they had completed a bunch of bonus objectives doing it this way—more than if they had chosen an easy path—so it probably was worth it.

The fact that there wasn’t any reward for saving the Dark Witch also didn’t really surprise him. It wasn’t part of their goals at all, after all, but just something Jake had done out of an odd sense of vanity. No… he had done it because it just felt wrong to let someone sacrifice themselves for his gain, so he had done all he could to stop that from happening. Even if it had wasted time and led to him damaging his Soulspace, he didn’t regret it a single bit, and would gladly do it aga—

Extraordinary Message: Additional achievement(s) based on unpredicted performance on the previous floor are being processed. Reward(s) pending; please wait.

Not that Jake was going to say no if the Wyrmgod and the system decided that an extra reward was in order.

“I did fear for a moment that Nevermore would not recognize what you did,” the Sword Saint said, smiling at Jake. “I am pleasantly surprised it does.”

“Yeah,” Dina said, nodding. “It isn’t surprising that there is no set achievement for it… I don’t think anyone else in C-grade could have cured her unless they had a Transcendent skill or a Bloodline allowing them to uniquely cure plagues.”

“Eh, I am sure someone else could find a way.” Jake smiled, waving it off. Underestimating what others were capable of was never a good idea, and just looking at his four party members, Jake knew there were some real monsters out there.

“No, I don’t think they could,” Dina said, shaking her head. “It took a unique combination of skills and abilities. Moreover, you had to handle the backlash of an angry Karmic Plague created by an early S-grade. The sheer level of pressure on your soul should have been suffocating… though I guess you never do tend to feel that kind of pressure.”

Jake was about to protest when he stopped himself. Well, okay, he had to admit, he wasn’t even aware there was meant to be some weird pressure from the Karmic Plague… Or, wait, was that what the drop of blood from Villy had promptly squashed the second he ate it? It was possible… Either way, Dina probably did have a point. Even if someone else could replicate what he had done, chances were that no one had done it yet in this incarnation of Nevermore.

“Let us just hope that the reward matches the uniqueness of the feat,” the Fallen King said. “I shall meditate till the reward is done calculating. I would presume it is ill-advised to leave here before that is done.”

“I concur, and shall meditate for a while too,” the old man said as he found a nice spot to sit down. “Even if using a Glimpse does not take much out of me, it isn’t as simple as merely consuming a few resources.”

Dina did the same, with Sylphie deciding to take a nap on Jake’s lap while he went through some stuff of his own.

While it could be argued that saving the Dark Witch had just been a moment of selfish vanity for Jake that didn’t actually do much, the process by which it had happened certainly benefitted him. Two skills had been upgraded, even if their rarity remained unchanged, and this downtime was the perfect opportunity to go through them.

First up was Touch of the Malefic Viper, which had gotten an even longer description.

[Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – With a single touch, the Malefic Viper seizes control of the world. Attempt to inject toxic energy into a being through contact. The nature of the toxic energy is determined by the user. The alchemist can only use toxic effects he has concocted or created, or further empower an existing toxic effect within a chosen target. Allows the alchemist to far more effectively control all toxins he is in contact with when using Touch of the Malefic Viper. Can be used to cultivate toxins of various forms. Can be used with all compatible types of mana affinities, further altering the effects. This effect is especially effective using your arcane affinity. Vastly increases the potency of transmutations made using Touch of the Malefic Viper at the cost of partly binding them to your soul. Some effects cannot be replicated. Adds an increase to the effectiveness of Touch of the Malefic Viper based on Intelligence and Wisdom. Passively provides 9 Intelligence per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper (C-grade variant). May your touch be the catalyst of corruption as you bend the world to your will.

Reading through it, it was mostly the same outside of the upgrade from 3 stat points a level to 9, and the added clarification that he only got 9 stat points for every level in the C-grade variant of the profession. Besides that, there was only one place with any changes, as far as he could see.

“Allows the alchemist to far more effectively control all toxins he is in contact with when using Touch of the Malefic Viper. Can be used to cultivate toxins of various forms.”

This part had already been there, but it had changed to be a lot more general, and when focusing on the skill, Jake felt unsure as to whether he had even lost any of the effects of Cultivate Toxin. Upon further inspection, he did find one downside to the merge.

Before, he could just use it on any toxin, and it would be cultivated. Now it only worked on toxins that he already had some level of familiarity with, or in other words, types of toxins he had eaten before. This did seem like a big downside, considering he wouldn’t be able to cultivate powerful and unique natural treasures using Cultivate Toxin, but on second thought, why wouldn’t he just use Palate and eat those with the special internal stomach, which would already allow him to learn from the item?

Yeah, didn’t seem like a big downside. Jake could also still use it to cultivate plants and such. In fact, this part was strictly better as far as he could see, considering he would now cultivate using a skill related to the Malefic Viper, and there had to be some Record-related benefits to that.

Moving on to the second upgraded skill, Jake saw a few more changes with this one.

[Palate of the Malefic Viper (Legendary)] – The Malefic Viper has honed its venom by devouring myriad toxins and treasures found throughout the multiverse. In the same vein, the Alchemist of the Malefic Viper can consume toxins to learn their effects and properties. Further evolved, you can now also learn the properties of herbs while at the same time enjoying a greater benefit from all potions consumed. Natural treasures can be swallowed and refined at an accelerated pace using your current level of Touch of the Malefic Viper (Legendary). If the item is not a toxin, the item will still be refined but at a slower pace. Allows you to learn the properties of any treasure in your stomach as you slowly refine it. Allows the alchemist to fully consume a swallowed item, destroying it in the process if possible. If the item cannot be destroyed or the result of its destruction is too violent, the alchemist will suffer a backlash, and the internal space will be damaged. Grants immunity or resistance to most poisons. Passively provides 9 Endurance per level in Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper (C-grade variant). Through endless consumption, may your power grow; through gluttony, may your Records expand as you devour the world.

Ignoring the equally ridiculous length of the description, the same thing with more stat points and clarification that it was only for the C-grade variant of his profession were both present in this one. Besides that, there were two changes. One was the addition of Touch of the Malefic Viper now being used, and the changed wording around that addition. The second one was the ability to fully consume an item, which Jake had not directly aimed at doing but had ended up unlocking pretty accidentally during his recklessness.

“Allows the alchemist to fully consume a swallowed item, destroying it in the process if possible. If the item cannot be destroyed or the result of its destruction is too violent, the alchemist will suffer a backlash, and the internal space will be damaged.”

This sentence pretty much summed up what Jake had ended up doing with that World Core, including the part where the internal space got damaged. Seeing it described as part of the skill was honestly a big relief to Jake, as it made it clear this was “intended” damage, giving him hope it would heal naturally with time. He would still need to have Eternal Hunger finish eating all the remnant energy before the repair could begin, but hopefully, he wouldn’t stumble upon an awesome treasure he wanted to eat before Palate was ready again.

Satisfied with seeing the two skills improve, he also noted these two upgrades provided an immediate boost of 180 Intelligence and 180 Endurance before all bonuses. What’s more, he would get even more stat points with every level-up… No matter how Jake looked at it, these Malefic Viper skills were truly overpowered, and he was all for it.

The upgrades, along with the entire curing process, had naturally also rewarded levels. Two of them, in fact.

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 228 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper] has reached level 229 - Stat points allocated, +35 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 228 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

Jake noted he was just one level away from getting his very first skill selection in C-grade, and while it was tempting to just grind out that level immediately, he couldn’t just make his party wait.

Seeing as the processing of whatever bonus achievement they would get wasn’t done yet, Jake also entered meditation while pulling out his Soulflame Cradle—that was the mentally shortened name he’d chosen—and infused some more arcane energy while checking on the situation within it. Nothing much had really happened on that front, as he was still waiting for his arcane affinity to get a proper foothold in the Cradle’s world.

A few minutes later, Jake and everyone else exited meditation simultaneously, finally getting the notification.

Calculations of extraordinary achievement completed. Special Grand Achievement earned based on actions performed, with majority contribution from Nevermore participant Jake Thayne.

Special Grand Achievement earned: Allow the Dark Witch to survive while successfully curing her of the Karmic Plague. 500 Nevermore Points earned. Due to completing a Grand Achievement, you will receive a 5% multiplier to all Nevermore Points at the final calculation.

Jake stared at it for a while. 500 points wasn’t much… but 5% extra points was.

“Is this really… okay?” Jake questioned out loud. The implication that this kind of Special Grand Achievement could even be earned honestly scared him a bit. What had other people gotten that he wasn’t aware of? Was that why they had been behind at times on previous floors?

“Jake,” the Sword Saint said, “when you get a good thing, you just smile and nod.”

“But—”

“Smile and nod.”

Jake and company appeared on the next floor not long after, having all recovered. This time, they found themselves standing on a cliffside, overlooking a city below with a large compound right in the middle. Within that compound was a training ground directly in their line of sight, and Jake’s attention was instantly drawn there even before the welcome message appeared.

Welcome to the forty-second floor of Nevermore: The Aloft Empire

You have arrived on a large planet ruled by the Aloft Empire, a faction ruled by a powerful A-grade emperor. More specifically, you find yourself within the land controlled by the Lunevile family, a small noble faction with an early C-grade leader at its helm.

Soon, the Lunevile family will attract some attention from forces they cannot handle. Uncover the nature of why the Lunevile family has become so conspicuous and ultimately decide their fate.

Note: Attracting the ire of the Altoft Royal Family will result in automatic elimination from the forty-second floor and require the party to start over.

Main objective: Decide the fate of the Lunevile family without drawing the ire of the Aloft Royal Family.

Bonus objectives: N/A

Current progress: Fate Determined (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 68,373

As Jake read the entire thing over, he already had a guess as to what this floor would be about. Especially coupled with what he saw down in the courtyard.

“This is an even trickier one,” the Sword Saint muttered. “If the emperor is A-grade, simply fighting our way through is out of the question… Scratch that; just making the royal family angry will result in an automatic loss…”

“This floor is another attempt to teach us the rules of the multiverse,” Jake said, shaking his head.

“What makes you think that?” Dina asked.

“That guy.” Jake pointed at a kid down in the courtyard swinging a sword. He looked no more than nine or ten years old and was only E-grade, but Jake’s attention had instantly been drawn to him the second they entered.

“His form is simple yet shows some promise, but I cannot see what else is special about him?” the Sword Saint questioned.

“Dina?” Jake asked.

“I can’t see anything either… Wait… I think…” Dina’s eyes opened in realization.

“Yep.” Jake smiled. “Kid’s got a Bloodline.”

While many would argue that two didn’t make a pattern… well, Jake was pretty sure he knew what to expect of this floor and several of the floors to come. He felt like they had just been thrown into a forced education plan on multiversal laws and etiquette.

Something the coming years would only further confirm.

Chapter 71

Level 230 Profession Skill Selection

So… skill selections. It had been a good while since Jake had one, and he would be lying to himself if he claimed he hadn’t been at least a little bit excited. Especially when it was his very first one in C-grade. The fact that he had gotten it while just sitting around, waiting on a flying ship had definitely increased his enjoyment, too.

He hadn’t rushed it, though. Usually, Jake wanted to jump right into them, but there was honestly no need to, especially not now that he had reached C-grade. While it was true that there could be some negative consequences to delaying picking a skill—primarily, ending up getting worse options—the opposite was also true. For some factions, it was even pretty normal to delay skill selections until you had practiced a certain technique or magic with the hope of getting a skill.

This was also why there wasn’t even a warning about negative consequences for waiting with the skill selection prompt, contrary to evolutions. He also wouldn’t have to delay that long. Leveling-wise, floor forty-two had honestly been shit, as they’d spent most of their time running and hiding, and with Jake having to constantly be on watch, he’d barely found any time to do alchemy. That was why he had only ended up getting his profession level while waiting in the capital of the Aloft Empire to meet the Emperor, at which point waiting just a few weeks more for the in-between room wasn’t out of the question.

So that was what he did. But Jake was still Jake, and his patience did have limits, especially when he didn’t just have a profession to choose skills, but a class to pick for, too.

After entering the boring in-between room, Jake excused himself from the party while the other four went to meditate by themselves to fully recover their resources. He found a nice corner to sit in and, with high expectations and anticipation, began.

Considering his profession had reached 230 first, it was only right to start with that.

*Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper profession skills available*

Accepting the prompt, Jake saw five options appear, making him smile. His smile did fade a bit when he saw the total list had shrunken quite a lot, as many of the skills he had been offered in prior skill selections were now gone.

Though, on second thought, it probably didn’t actually matter that much, did it? He rarely went back and picked skills he had already been offered.

Shaking his head, Jake’s smile returned as he turned his attention to the skills on display. Man, I have missed this.

He was going to take his time going over every single skill on offer; that was for sure. Starting with quite an interesting one.

[Conjure Virtual Mind (Epic)] – What is better than one mind? Two. Create a simulation of your mind that can think autonomously and develop ideas. This will be a clone of your mind and thus still limited by your current Records. Can only exist within your Soulspace and cannot directly influence anything around it or manipulate any energy. All information between you and your virtual mind must be relayed orally or telepathically. The duration of the virtual mind and its level of sophistication are determined by Wisdom, Willpower, and Intelligence.

The first skill, and the system started out by offering an epic-rarity one. This was the C-grade version of epic rarity, too, making it even better. It was akin to the very first skill offered in D-grade being ancient rarity… or maybe not. Either way, the first skill offered was sure something.

This seemed like the first step in creating an avatar, and he had quite a lot of ideas as to why he’d been offered the skill. The first was naturally sim-Jake, who had not merely been a simulated mind, but effectively a separate version of himself. The second source of inspiration was maybe Minaga and his cloning ability… but that one was a bit of a stretch. Of course, it was also entirely possible this was just a basic skill most people got offered around this point in their Path, as cloning or at least avatar creation did seem like a pretty basic technique for most considered truly powerful.

Needless to say, this skill would be far from an actual avatar, as the Virtual Mind was rife with limitations. Enough limitations for him to write it off pretty quickly, and not just for the “low” rarity. The real problem with it was… the Virtual Mind was made for thinking and not doing… and Jake recognized he wasn’t the best thinker. He was the type to do stuff until something worked. Or, in fancier words, he preferred doing practical, empirical experiments to find solutions rather than relying on studying and theory.

In less simple terms, he wasn’t the smartest cookie in the drawer, and having another mind to think up dumb ideas wasn’t going to help him with anything.

Hence, he moved on to the next one… which he felt like he had seen before.

[Arcane Alchemist’s Grand Purification (Epic)] – Embrace your arcane affinity as you stabilize what properties you desire and destroy the unwanted. Attempt to purify any alchemical ingredient, reducing it to its most basic state while ensuring its stability. Arcane purification can help destroy unwanted properties from an ingredient, making it purer. Must have suitable ingredients. Purification does not require any additional tools or equipment, but the skill’s effect can be amplified with the use of certain catalysts. Adds a small increase to the effectiveness and chance of success of attempted purifications based on Wisdom and Intelligence.

WARNING: This skill is unlocked by, and will serve as an upgrade to, your Alchemist’s Purification.

Yep, he had definitely seen this one before. Thinking back, hadn’t that also been during his first skill selection in D-grade? Yeah, he was pretty sure it had been. The only difference was that it had now added Grand to the skill name, which had seemingly allowed it to even retain its epic-rarity tag. There was probably some more stuff in the updated description, but Jake wasn’t overly interested.

Jake had skipped it in D-grade because the skill seemed like something he could easily do himself… which was still the case. So, why hadn’t he? Well, the thing was, purification was usually used to bring an ingredient to a desired state or to “fix” ingredients with problems. The first of these reasons required the person to have a pre-known theoretical reason for wanting to purify an ingredient and remove properties rather than just doing it during the crafting process. The second reason one would purify an ingredient and “fix” it was its subpar quality, and… well…

Jake was a rich, asshole Chosen who only got the best of the best, and even when he didn’t, his entire Path of alchemy was just to make stuff work by throwing it together. He had very basic plans and outlines of what he wanted to do, but he didn’t draw up entire tomes of research before crafting every poison. Jake remembered seeing some of the notebooks Reika had made, and it was intense…

Anyway, the mere fact Jake hadn’t upgraded the skill on his own already was proof enough that he didn’t need this. Since reaching D-grade, Jake couldn’t recall using the skill whatsoever outside of purifying water a few times. Usually, if he wanted something gone, he would only figure that out during the crafting process, at which point he could easily remove it with a bit of destructive arcane energy.

Sure, it did suck to look at the inferior-rarity skill, but at this point, Jake was just waiting to find a use for it or to merge it with one of his other skills. Probably one of his Legacy skills… and if he wanted to do that, then picking an upgrade like this would only make that fusion process more difficult.

To summarize, Jake didn’t need it, and picking it could even turn out to be detrimental down the line. So… next skill. And this one moved him up to ancient rarity.

[Arcane Curse Manifestation (Ancient)] – Allows the alchemist to condense pure curse energy into objects known as Curse Fragments by stabilizing the volatile curse energy using your arcane affinity and encasing it in stable arcane mana. These Curse Fragments can be used in rituals, as alchemical ingredients, and as catalysts in crafting and transmutation. Curse Fragments cannot be effectively used directly as weapons. Be warned that wielding the power of curses can lead to unexpected results and requires a high level of control. Curse Fragments left unattended may begin to influence the world around them. The quality and amount of curse energy that can be put into Curse Fragments depends on Wisdom and Willpower.

This wasn’t Jake’s first time being offered a curse-related skill for his profession, and it certainly wasn’t going to be the last. The last time had been right after he had created Eternal Hunger, and truth be told, the entire concept of curses had very much spooked him back then—especially considering he had just managed to fight off the influence of Eternal Hunger. Thus, when offered Condense Curse Marble, skipping it had been a no-brainer, as his use of a Sin weapon had just been temporary, not part of who he was.

Now, things weren’t quite that simple.

Whether he liked it or not, curse energy was now a big part of his Path. Eternal Hunger wasn’t going anywhere; it would stick with him until the day he died or managed to figure out a way to separate it from himself… if that was even something he wanted.

Jake had to admit that he wasn’t entirely averse to his increased reliance on curse energy. He hadn’t even hesitated to use it when he absorbed the World Core, as he knew it was a wellspring of energy that was still growing by the day. A source of energy that Jake was uniquely qualified to control. While his affinity for dark mana was great, his ability to tame and control curse energy was far superior, and coupled with his Bloodline, he probably could have become a damn good curse mage or something if that was what he wanted.

There was also the fact that sim-Jake had effectively usurped whatever instinctual presence Eternal Hunger had when it relied on its chimera form. Eternal Shadow, his only mythical skill, was also tied up in the use of curse energy.

All of this is to say Jake had come to accept that curses were now part of him. That being the case, Jake also had to face the reality that he didn’t use curse energy nearly as much as he could or should, but only relied on it for special circumstances or with a limited number of skills. Which, in retrospect, was honestly silly when he had one place where he could apply curse energy with great effectiveness: his poisons.

And Arcane Curse Manifestation was a way to do just that. It was a way to begin integrating curses into his alchemy and create interesting and potentially more powerful poisons. He could even use these Curse Fragments for rituals if he wanted…

Yeah, this one was definitely a contender. Of course, it all depended on the last two skills. The first of which was… something.

[Malefic Plague Theory (Legendary)] – To kill an enemy, you use poison; to destroy a world, you deploy a plague. Allows the alchemist to research and potentially create plagues of various natures. Plagues are incredibly complex self-replicating toxins that can spread independently of the creator by taking root in each infected target and using them as carriers. Do be warned that plagues can mutate and are incredibly difficult to control; thus, incredible caution and patience is advised when working on them. Malefic properties linger in all plagues you create, making them more potent and allowing them to spread faster. Stat bonuses are dependent on the nature of the plague.

Although Jake had seen this one coming, he hadn’t expected the first-ever plague-related skill he was offered to be legendary. He wasn’t even entirely sure if the skill deserved that rarity… until he read the second-to-last sentence. Malefic properties.

Anything with malefic properties had to be powerful, right? Jake assumed it meant the skill borrowed from the malefic affinity, which he was pretty sure only his Legacy skills did under normal circumstances. It certainly made the rather normal-looking, warning-filled skill look quite a bit more impressive.

The reason he had been so certain he would be offered something like this was due to just how much knowledge related to plagues had been jammed into his head. From both Palate and Sagacity, mind you, as the two of them had tag-teamed him in unlocking a flood of knowledge from the drop of blood when he healed the Dark Witch.

This knowledge did also make Jake aware of just how little he wanted the skill. And it wasn’t just because of the multiverse generally not being a fan of plagues—Jake was pretty damn sure he could get away with researching and even making plagues with his identity as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper—but because he knew just how useless they would be for his Path.

Plagues, from a combat perspective, sucked ass. They were only good for killing people far weaker than the creator and wiping out entire civilizations. Why in the hell would Jake want to spend a shitload of time cooking up a plague, only for it to work on people way weaker than himself? That would just be a waste of time, which was why he had no interest in the skill. Oh, yeah, and there were moral reasons for skipping it. Can’t forget those.

Moving on to the final offering, one thing instantly caught his attention.

The rarity.

He could barely believe his eyes when he saw it. The very first mythical skill he had ever been offered in a skill selection.

[Hallowed Shroud of the Heretic-Chosen (Mythical)] – To follow the Path of one who is blessed, yet a heretic, is both audacious and auspicious, but there is safety to be found for those who follow the Heretic-Chosen of the Malefic Viper. Your very presence as a Heretic-Chosen helps protect those around you who follow a similar Path, hiding their identities as heretics by masking them as blessed instead. All those hidden under your shroud also experience a growth in Records gained related to the Path of the Heretic-Blessed. This skill partly borrows Records from your Shroud of the Primordial skill, making it work even against beings of divine nature. The shroud has no effective range but covers everyone who follows you regardless of where they are. Walk with confidence and spread your Path as all those who follow in your footsteps are protected by your Hallowed Shroud. The effectiveness of Hallowed Shroud of the Heretic-Chosen is improved by Wisdom and Willpower.

“Why is it shit?” Jake muttered to himself while sitting in the corner of the in-between room.

“You got offered a bad skill?” the Sword Saint questioned, having heard Jake complain and aware he was doing a skill selection. Jake hadn’t exactly been subtle about his impatience to finish the floor and have a proper calm period to do it.

“Well, it’s mythical.”

“Oh? That sounds incred—”

“And it sucks ass,” Jake interrupted with a sigh.

“If I may, could I ask why you judge it so?” the old man asked.

“It is strong for what it does, sure, but it isn’t really something I want. All it does is help hide people and increase their Record growth, but only in relation to the specific Path that I don’t even think anyone else is following…”

“You are referring to that Path of both having a Blessing and being considered a heretic?”

Jake was about to confirm when he stopped himself. He… was pretty sure he’d never openly talked about his identity as a Heretic-Chosen, so how—

“I can confess I, too, was offered skills related to such a Path, and I put two and two together and realized it originated from you.” The old man shook his head. “From what I have gathered, it comes from the innate resistance to gods you carry and allow others to also experience. It makes you inherently able to question things and stand in defiance of the gods—which treating them merely as equals apparently counts as. Aware of it or not, I believe you passively convert anyone you interact with a lot into a bit of a heretic, whether or not any of you intend for that to be the case.”

“I see.” Jake nodded. Yeah, it probably made sense they were offered skills like that with Jake’s passive influence, right? Which begged the question… “Did you pick any of those skills?”

“No,” the Sword Saint said, chuckling. “I have no need to, and they don’t fit my Path. Plus, they all seem to revolve around you, and while I have nothing against you, Jake, I am not going to tie my Path to you.”

Jake listened and slowly nodded… realizing the old man had just hit the nail on the head as to why he was so damn reluctant to pick up skills like this mythical-rarity Shroud. He didn’t like the thought of people following him, or a horde of people looking up to him and relying on him, giving up their own personhood to follow some Path they believed Jake would want them to follow.

He wasn’t trying to start some huge movement of Heretic-Blessed, as the system called it in the skill. If people wanted to take inspiration from him and go that route? Sure, go ahead, but he wasn’t going to actively pursue the Path of being some prophet himself or encouraging others to do so. It would be their choice, and any skill that encouraged others to follow the Path was a skill he didn’t want. He preferred for the people around him to be equals and friends, not subordinates.

“Thanks,” Jake muttered.

The old man just nodded and smiled, having seemingly read his thoughts. “Becoming a symbol or someone others look up to isn’t something one can control. It will happen naturally as one nears the peak of power. People will always stare toward the sky in awe, and if they see you among the clouds, so will they be in awe of you.”

“Yeah,” Jake said, sighing.

“You can accept but not embrace it. In the end, you cannot control what others do, but you can control how you react to their actions. You are not responsible for others unless you want to be. It is not their right to put that pressure on you, so just choose what you believe you can live with and be true to yourself, even if that disregards the feelings of others. Or, I guess what I am saying is… go with your gut. That seems to have worked out well for you thus far.”

Jake nodded and smiled. The old man was right. He would just do what felt right to him.

That was why he happily picked Malefic Plague Theory to end all of existence and spread death and destruction to the entire multiverse!

All jokes aside, there really was only one skill that truly appealed to him out of these five.

So, pretty happy with his choice, and after only a little more deliberation while checking over prior skill offerings, he picked Arcane Curse Manifestation.

It was time to finally make some truly cursed poisons.

Chapter 72

Meetings... So Many Meetings

The Chosen Ceremony Support Group (CCSG) held yet another biweekly meeting. Six women met at Jake’s residence, as that was one of the only places where they could be sure no one would interrupt or interfere. All of them were united by one thing:

They each had a personal relationship with Jake and had been severely impacted by his identity as a Chosen. No, they were still repeatedly impacted by his status.

This group consisted of Reika, Meira, Scarlett, Irin, Bastilla, and Izil, though they sometimes had others join who also suffered from their association with Jake being revealed. These meetings didn’t have any strict purpose… Well, they had initially been a way to organize and get their stories straight with what information they could and couldn’t share about Jake, but after only three meetings, the group had turned into what was essentially just a support group for venting.

“My family has constantly been sending people asking me if I could get a meeting with the Chosen, and when I said he is in Nevermore, they began to question if I knew which floor he was at, and one of my aunts even asked why I didn’t join the party,” Bastilla, the beastfolk roommate of Reika, complained. “I barely even know him… We did one dungeon together! Why the hell would he bring me, of all people?”

“Have you tried misdirecting them?” Izil, the elf from the Altmar Empire, offered. “I keep telling them that I switched strategies from directly trying to make a close connection with the Chosen to instead focusing on the people around him who do have a close connection… which means they are actively supporting me going to these meetings now, as they think I am networking. Which I guess I kind of am. But it also makes them back off, at least for a time.”

“That’s a good strategy,” Reika said, nodding. “I am lucky that I have no pressure from family anymore. Then again, that is mainly because the Patriarch is already close to Jake. Ah, by the way, as an update, the other alchemists from the clan have also backed off on trying to get closer to Jake through me, and I warned them that trying to take advantage of the fact that he brought them here may end badly. No, what I have had trouble with recently was this instructor who had a lesson I really wanted to take about ice-affinity flask brewing. The man is a total creeper who immediately refunded any Academy Credits I had spent on the lesson and then proceeded to offer private lessons. I thought he wanted… you know… but no, he just wanted intel on Jake.”

“Wait… isn’t that the same guy who taught cold-poison absorption and refinement?” Scarlett said in realization. “Big, blue scalekin. Has a weird scale pattern on his chest that looks a bit like a cupcake?”

“That’s the one!” Reika confirmed. “Geez, he tried it with you too?”

“Yeah, he definitely isn’t subtle,” Scarlett said. “I think he is from one of the Dragonflights or something, though I didn’t actually talk to him; I just took the refund and informed him I was forbidden from speaking about the Chosen. He still sent me a natural treasure even after I told him to screw off, so I just ate it and moved on.” She ended with a shrug.

“Definitely nothing wrong with taking advantage of people like that; just be careful not to sow any debts,” Reika said, nodding with a smile. She then turned to look at Meira, who was sitting quietly as usual. “Anything new happen for you over the last two weeks? Still the same problem?”

“Yeah…” Meira said meekly. “I don’t even try to take normal lessons anymore. Only if it is really necessary. I just work with Teacher.”

Meira had the problem of being more than just the former slave and close associate of the Chosen. She was now also the first person that Duskleaf, the Grand Elder of the Order, had blessed in no one knew how long, making her a figure many were interested in. Coupled with her demeanor and general personality, that was not a good mix, as she was far from used to the pressure.

Scarlett did have a bit of the same problem, being blessed by the Malefic Viper herself, but it was far, far from as severe as it was for Meira. The six of them had all questioned why Jake was so insistent on staying anonymous, but now, after having experienced even the second-hand impact of his status, they got it. While there were many advantages, the sheer mental drain was exhausting.

You had to consider whether every single person talking to you had some ulterior motive, not wanting to talk with you as a person but just using you to get to someone else. This was one of the reasons why these meetings kept happening: It was nice to talk to a group of people who didn’t just suffer from the same issue, but who you were also relatively sure weren’t just there to try and get closer to Jake.

“Any positive stories?” Reika asked, trying to focus on the good stuff.

“I got one!” Irin said. “My former supervisor, who just came back from an assignment a week ago, keeps inviting me out for drinks and asking to chat. This was the same girl who, just a decade ago, made fun of me for not landing any big fish in the net.” She shook her head as she displayed a proud smile. “I still remember when she spent three full hours bragging about getting with this young scion from some big beastfolk tribe while throwing in her jabs, asking me who I managed to snatch up recently. Not a single comment from her for the last week, and I even purposefully keep bumping into her.”

“Devilish,” Izil said, chuckling. “Speaking of devilish… you said you had a skill selection coming up. Did you… you know?”

“Get an option related to Jake? No.” Irin waved her off, smiling. “I got three total. Two for my race and one for my profession.”

“And?” Reika questioned.

“Only picked one of them.”

“Really?” Reika said with a deadpan face.

“Best option by far—don’t blame me,” Irin said, shameless. “It isn’t like I am the only one.”

Reika sighed. “Still.”

“Alright, change of subject. You know what I am gonna ask, right? What’s the tally for the last two weeks? I am at thirteen. Down from last week. I think people are beginning to get the message.”

“Only forty-three,” Reika said with a smile. “All of them in-person, too, with half during a single lesson.”

“A hundred and two,” Bastilla said with a sigh. “Most from back home… I don’t think they get that I don’t actually know the Chosen, like, at all.”

“Just eight; I think the fact that I have a fiancé back home got around.” Izil smiled. “I don’t have one, but it worked.”

“A hundred and seventy-nine,” Scarlett said quite proudly. “I rejected all of them… especially this super-weird one.”

All eyes turned to the final girl in the room, who suddenly looked embarrassed.

“Meira?”

“I don’t…”

“Come on,” Izil said. “It can’t be that many, right?”

With some hesitation, she said, “Nine hundred and five…”

The others stared at her for a moment before Irin began giggling to herself.

“That’s on me,” Izil said, raising her hands in defeat. “I accidentally let a bit too much slip to the Empire… so…”

“It’s okay.” Meira smiled. “I just ignore them…”

As for what they were counting?

Unprompted invitations. Invitations varied, with most of them being proposals or people asking them out, along with factions that wanted meetings to establish a connection—with the goal of recruiting them, naturally. Oh, and the odd ones, like this weird guy who just wanted Scarlett to bite him.

Life as a survivor of knowing Jake was truly challenging.

In a meeting room back on Earth, other associates of Jake were also working hard to deal with everything Jake’s identity as the Chosen of the Malefic Viper brought about.

“Any problems on your end, Arthur?” Miranda asked the man sitting across the large table. “I heard a demonstration recently got a bit out of control in… What was it called again?”

“Seawind Village, though we should probably update the name to Seawind City with its expansion over the last year,” Arthur explained. “There was a recent influx of immigrant beastfolk who preferred to live closer to the ocean, and the locals didn’t exactly take to this kindly. Especially not when the housing prices rose exponentially for all residences that were seaside, pricing out anyone who wasn’t at least solidly in D-grade.” He shook his head. “While we managed to quell some of the anger by assuring that those who already owned housing there would be grandfathered into the new real-estate law without having to pay increased taxes for at least the next five years, many who wanted to move there in the future are still far from happy, and as you say, there was one protest recently that got out of hand. A few injured, but no deaths.”

“I take it you have the situation handled, or do you need more assistance?” Miranda questioned.

“No, I believe that after an adaptation period, things will calm down. We are also working on some high-rise construction that will provide more affordable accommodations that still offer a view of the sea, even if they are not close to it. Many of the beastkin want quick access to the sea itself due to their variant races, while the humans only really care about the view.”

Miranda nodded, happy that things seemed to be working out but more than a little tired of dealing with issues like this all the time. Even before the mass influx of slaves had appeared—an influx that was still ongoing, mind you—they had been working on reforming many of the laws and institutions present on Earth to make what would effectively be a proper government.

Ever since the integration, it had become the norm for every City Lord to effectively be the local warlord who made their own rules and laws. While the United City Alliance and other factions did integrate many cities, they didn’t include even close to every single city. Especially not the rural ones.

Since the establishment of the council, they had actively made an effort to unite the planet. With the influx of slaves, this only became even more of a priority to make sure fringe factions that opposed this immigration wouldn’t appear without their knowledge. Recently, the United Tribes had been sending arrivals to help assist Miranda, and while they were a great aid in expanding the influence of the council, they were also ultimately newcomers, which many native earthlings weren’t big fans of. Lots of xenophobia all around; that was for sure.

“Speaking of beastkin and beast, did you look into the appearance of the C-grade beast?” Miranda asked another guy in the room. It was the former leader of the fort, and now, after the Myriad Paths event, a reformed, fist-fighting magic brawler. Phillip.

Phillip had given up entirely on being a leader of any kind, even after his second wind from having to deal with Haven during the Ell’Hakan debacle. He was now thoroughly retired… if by retired, one meant having taken up the job of working for the government as an investigator of sorts, that is. Ah, but he was not a leader with any employee responsibility. That had been his big requirement for taking the job.

He had recently gone to investigate what was suspected to be the first appearance of a C-grade beast within human territory since Sylphie. C-grades were still pretty rare on Earth, so this had caused some ruckus, especially given that the beast had appeared in a rural village with no other C-grades anywhere nearby. All other C-grades, Jake—or now Miranda, having been given the authority—had to approve to enter protected human lands. The one exception were those who had grown up within these lands and evolved there, like Sylphie. And now this beast.

“Yes, I looked into it, and I don’t think there will be any problems even if we leave him alone.” Phillip shook his head and smiled. “In fact, this beast has apparently been protecting the locals in the area for quite a while and is a bit of a local hero. Plus, he was really nice… though he did seem to have the same issue as Sylphie where he refuses to properly communicate, even if by all accounts he should be able to.”

“Alright, good to know,” Miranda said, nodding. “Keep an eye out still; better safe than sorry.” In all honesty, she wasn’t that surprised. From the reports, the beast was friendly and had been living with humans ever since they returned from the tutorial, all without any incidents of note.

It did make sense. Golden retrievers tended to be good boys and girls, so it would have been very surprising if it had turned into a bad dog.

Miranda smiled at the thought as she turned to one of the estate developers who had been allowed to attend the meeting. “Moving on. Could you give me an update on clearing the buffer zone around Haven? Did you relocate all the illegal settlements as planned?”

Quite a while ago, it had been decided that a buffer zone of around ten kilometers would be made around the entrance to the forest Haven was placed in. This was to continue respecting Jake’s wish of having Haven be a quaint little forest town, with the hope he would actually bother still visiting there from time to time.

Without this buffer zone, Haven would rapidly turn into a metropolis, as every new arrival wanted to be as close to the Chosen of the Malefic Viper as possible. Why wouldn’t they? Their primary reason for coming had been to form a better relationship with the Order of the Malefic Viper, after all.

Despite having set up the buffer zone, some people still chose to settle there. It was a constant struggle, having to clear them out, and Miranda was honestly considering just placing a hex on the entire zone to give anyone who spent too long there horrible waking nightmares. Maybe diarrhea, too.

“Yes, Mistress, they have all been moved to the primary city, and better signage has been posted to clearly state that settling within the buffer zone is not allowed,” the female developer explained. “However, Mistress, if I may, we are beginning to run out of raw materials… The supply simply cannot meet the demand. We are especially in need of metals for reinforcing the structures.”

“Hm, try to talk with the merchant alliance about obtaining more,” Miranda said after thinking for a bit. “Lillian can update your budget, but I will need an itemized report of what you spend these funds on. We don’t want a repeat of Ricardo, do we?”

The woman nodded nervously. “No… No, of course not. I will make sure not a single Credit is out of place.”

Yeah, Ricardo had been… well, foolhardy was perhaps the right word? Actually, stupidly greedy was probably more accurate. He had thought he could skim off the top without anyone noticing just because the budding government was still young and disorganized. Little had the guy known that the leader of the merchant alliance on Earth was Sultan, and when Lillian noticed discrepancies, the guy was fucked. Sultan was shrewd, so he at least knew how to take advantage of Miranda and Jake in a way that wouldn’t annoy them too much.

This did introduce another issue: what to do with criminals? Luckily, the people from the United Tribes had some solutions there. While capital punishment was considered normal in the multiverse, it did feel like a bit much to execute anyone who committed any crimes, no matter how small. Others also had this issue, including the United Tribes, who had a solution to keep certain beasts with low intelligence penned.

That’s right—Earth had constructed its first proper jail. It couldn’t hold C-grades or D-grades of high power, but that luckily hadn’t been necessary yet, either. They had achieved this by instructing high-level crafters to make cells that were too durable for even the average high-level D-grade to leave a dent, further improving the place with a formation that weakened and drained resources from all those within. Finally, every single prisoner was magically marked to make them easier to track. With that, even if someone escaped, a C-grade guard could quite easily hunt them down.

Miranda was about to move on when Lillian tapped her on the shoulder and sent a telepathic message. “I was just informed that a warrior found an interesting item after slaying quite a powerful C-grade.”

Having a good idea of what she was talking about, Miranda requested the hunter’s presence.

A few minutes later, a familiar figure entered the room. A lot of slaves had come to Earth, with few standing out. This man was among the outstanding individuals who, after being freed, had willingly taken up a leadership position and become a great support for the council.

“Holstred, I hear you have been hunting?” Miranda said as she smiled at the former Knight Commander-turned-slave-turned-free man.

“Yes, Mistress,” he said with a bow, overly polite as ever. “I believe it would be of interest to the council to be aware that items such as these seem to have begun appearing across the planet.”

Holstred held up a black token depicting a large, black pit containing a dragon. Miranda did indeed already know what it was as she Identified it.

[Greater Nevermore Admittance Token (Unique)] – A special token that allows the user to teleport themselves and up to 99 others with them directly to Nevermore City to enter the World Wonder known as Nevermore. Nevermore consists of a number of sequential dungeons with increasing difficulty. Time is warped within Nevermore, making time pass slower outside than inside. One can only spend a total of 50 years within Nevermore. This token can be reused to return the same number of people back to where they originally teleported from.

Requirements: C-grade.

Miranda looked at the item and smiled slightly. If those tokens had begun to drop… it appeared another influx of newcomers to Nevermore was inbound.

Chapter 73

Level 230 Class Skill Selection

One skill selection was great.

Two skill selections? Now, that was just awesome. And today was truly an awesome day.

Jake was already pretty happy with his new profession skill, even if he didn’t have the chance to start experimenting with it right then and there. Sure, he would’ve liked to sit down for a few weeks and just make Curse Fragments to see if he could find anything to use them for immediately, but that didn’t mean he was any less excited to get another class skill or maybe even upgrade one of his existing ones.

In fact… having both skill selections at once was double-awesome, because it meant that it didn’t matter whether the next floor had a lot of downtime for crafting or was filled with combat; Jake would have something new and shiny to play with.

So, enjoying his good mood, Jake began the skill selection.

*Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge class skills available*

And he was instantly disappointed, because, as was almost becoming customary by now, there naturally had to be one shitty magic skill on offer.

[Devastating Arcane Orb (Rare)] – Harness your destructive arcane mana to bring devastation upon the world. Allows the Hunter to summon an explosive orb of arcane mana at a target location within range of perception. The arcane orb will be highly destructive and especially effective against environmental mana, with energies tailored to wide-scale destruction over focused damage, allowing each Devastating Arcane Orb to destroy large areas. Multiple orbs can be conjured at once for optimal devastation. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Intelligence when using Devastating Arcane Orb.

Man, Jake was definitely feeling regret now. He should totally have picked Malefic Plague Theory as his profession skill, as he now realized he had missed out on a huge opportunity. Imagine the synergy. With a plague, he would wipe out a civilization of E-grades, and then he could blow up their cities with Devastating Arcane Orbs once everyone was dead! One for killing, one for destroying—the perfect combo to wipe out people too weak to fight back.

Alas, Jake had failed to predict he would be offered such a perfect skill in his class skill selection.

All kidding aside, why the hell would Jake want a rare skill that was tailor-made to blow up stuff? Not even enemies, just… stuff. Also, the reasoning behind him being offered the skill felt pretty damn thin. Did it really all come from Jake blowing up some cities during floor forty-one? Sure, he did sometimes use highly destructive arcane magic to blow up large areas or as distractions, but enough for one of his five skill offerings to be taken up like this?

Yeah, it felt like it was a bullshit skill just there to fill the list. This was also somewhat true for the next one on offer, though at least there was some solid reasoning behind that one.

[Superior Arcane Armaments (Epic)] – Be it a weapon or armor, through your arcane mana, you shall never be found wanting. Allows the Hunter to intricately design and summon armaments of arcane mana. Armaments can be given to others. Weapons created will deal a small amount of bonus destructive arcane damage, while armor will be strengthened by the concept of stability. The duration and durability of all items summoned are based on the mana expended and the nature of the armament’s design. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Wisdom when using Superior Arcane Armaments. Additional bonuses may apply depending on the nature of the conjured item.

Jake still remembered being offered the skill Arcane Armaments several skill selections ago and thinking it was pretty cool. He also remembered that skill had been an upgrade to one called Summon Spectral Armaments or something like that.

Now, he did have to question… why was the system so damn insistent on him learning how to summon armor and weapons? Three instances of being offered effectively the same skill definitely felt like overkill. Additionally, why would he even need it in the first place? A summoned katar would definitely be worse than Blackpoint Blade, and way worse than Eternal Hunger. Could he maybe make some armor out of it? Nah, that also seemed bad, as Jake was fully dedicated to dodging stuff, and trying to gear himself out in arcane armor just seemed like it would weigh him down. The only real use cases Jake could see were making things for his allies, as he assumed even monsters could use summoned items like this, or summoning arrows… In other words, something he already had not one, but two skills doing.

Speaking of summoning arrows, Jake did feel pretty damn certain this upgrade to Superior Arcane Armaments came at least partly from his creation of Protean Arrow. Both were about designing things using arcane mana, after all. Of course, that upgrade had partly been facilitated by the Puzzle Cube that he had been gifted…

On second thought, Jake didn’t want to pursue any line of logic that would make him have any negative emotions towards that wonderful little box of puzzling wonders. The skill he’d been offered sucked and wasn’t something he needed, so he proceeded to the next one.

Things were finally starting to get interesting.

[Arcane Arrow Rain of Horizon’s Edge (Ancient)] – At your will, cover the horizon in a sea of arrows. Allows you to repeatedly clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties as one becomes hundreds. If the original arrow is shot upwards, it can be transformed into a devastating Arcane Arrow Rain, exploding as it releases a rainfall of arrows in a massive area. Cloning arcane arrows or creating Arcane Arrow Rains using arcane arrows has a far lower mana and stamina cost. On an internal cooldown, the Hunter can push himself beyond his usual abilities and create an arrow that, upon activation, will explode several times on a slight delay for multiple Arcane Arrow Rains. Doing this will temporarily make the skill unavailable. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Agility and Wisdom when using Arcane Arrow Rain. Increased damage based on Perception and the distance the arrows fall from when creating an Arcane Arrow Rain.

WARNING: This skill is unlocked by, and will serve as an upgrade to, your existing Splitting Arrow Rain, resulting in the loss of the skill.

A direct upgrade to Splitting Arrow Rain, more or less. One that was linked to his class, too, making it even more interesting. Reading over the actual effects, Jake was both impressed and a little unsure about this one’s upgrade path.

It was pretty clear the upgrade leaned heavily into just adding more arrows. Jake didn’t doubt that the basic splitting function would be even better than before, as well as the overall Arrow Rain aspect. Even the way the rain happened had improved, as rather than just mass-cloning the arrows, this skill would make one big arrow that would then explode and create an Arrow Rain.

The integration of his arcane affinity into the skill also had the effect of making the cloning of all arcane arrows—which was all of them—more cost-effective. This was honestly a pretty damn obvious upgrade he should probably implement himself if he didn’t take this skill. It seemed incredibly simple and was just something he had never considered. Adding his arcane affinity to the skill had never seemed relevant, as he was just copying arcane arrows anyway, so what would double arcane do? Well, make things more efficient, apparently.

This was already a pretty good basic upgrade. More arrows, better cost-efficiency, and a more effective method of creating Arrow Rains. All of it was great.

However, the most exciting thing about the skill by far was the option to put the skill on a cooldown in order to “push himself beyond his usual abilities” and create a self-sustaining Arcane Arrow Rain. If Jake read it correctly, using this effect would allow him to create a massive Arrow Rain that lasted for a prolonged period of time without him even needing to do anything.

Jake had never before run into any functionalities in skills like this one—or at least, not like this. Sure, Wings could trigger a powerful effect and then become unusable for a while, and Palate also kind of did this with its current situation—because, yes, on a side note, even one and a half years or so after having the World Core explode, his stomach still hadn’t fully healed.

Anyway, back to the Arrow Rain upgrade, Jake was very curious about how this worked. Like, what was the concept at work? Usually, things that allowed you to break your own limits were classified as boosting skills, and even extremely powerful single-cast spells usually came with either a long cast time, some form of backlash, or a period of weakness after use. This skill didn’t mention that Jake would experience any of this, only a cooldown. Just to find out exactly how that worked, Jake nearly wanted to select the skill, but he had to remain steadfast. There were two more options to go through, after all.

And the next one had a suspiciously similar line in the description.

[Penetrating Arcane Arrow of Horizon’s Edge (Ancient)] – No defenses shall stop your arrows as they pierce any foe that dares impede your Path toward the horizon. Allows the Hunter to create a Penetrating Arcane Arrow that will pierce through nearly any natural barriers and have a far higher penetrative effect on any defenses manifested or possessed by the target. Will temporarily lower the defenses of the foe if they are struck successfully. These effects grow more powerful as enemy defenses and the level disparity between you and your opponent increases. On an internal cooldown, the Hunter can push himself beyond his usual abilities and forcefully infuse the concepts of the Penetrating Arrow of Horizon’s Edge into another self-created arcane arrow. Doing this will temporarily make the skill unavailable, with the duration depending on the power of the arrow you infused. Due to conceptual synergy, Penetrating Arcane Arrow of Horizon’s Edge receives significantly increased bonuses from Unblemished Arrows of the Horizon. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Agility, Strength, Wisdom, Intelligence, and Perception when using Penetrating Arcane Arrow of Horizon’s Edge.

Again, there was the ability to “supercharge” the skill and put it on cooldown. Was this maybe something inherent to the Hunter of Horizon’s Edge class? Just as Avaricious was all about making his attacks more effective against higher-leveled foes, perhaps this concept allowed Jake to “supercharge” skills along with the usual bonuses.

If that was the case… why? What made this ability inherent to his class? Perception scaling made sense thematically with the concept of chasing the horizon. The horizon was just a metaphor for something unattainable that was incredibly far away, with any progress made toward the horizon just moving it further away. Perception played into this, as the further one could see, the more ambitious the horizon one chased. The scaling based on levels also made some level of sense, as every enemy reflected what obstructed him on his Path toward Horizon’s Edge, and every enemy was ahead of him on this endless journey.

The main theme of his class did seem to be going above and beyond, reaching for the impossible, so was this supercharging of skills maybe a representation of that? That he would reach beyond what was permitted to his station and, at the cost of putting the skill on a cooldown, supercharge the skill for one final push?

He knew he wouldn’t get an answer by just thinking about it, so he decided to evaluate the actual skill.

Penetrating Arrow seemed like a bunker-buster of sorts. It was designed to destroy defenses, and would probably work very well as an opener of sorts when Protean Arrow wasn’t an option. Or could he supercharge the skill and infuse the concept into the Protean Arrow? Yeah, that was definitely an option, too, if he went for the one-shot.

The increased synergy with Unblemished Arrows was also interesting, but honestly made sense considering the two skills were kind of similar. The skill was also ancient rarity, so it clearly dealt with high-level concepts… Yeah, all in all, this skill would just be a great tool to add to his skillset. Sure, he did have a few doubts, such as how long it would take to summon this Penetrating Arrow, but since it didn’t mention how fast or slow it would be, he assumed it wouldn’t be too bad or good.

In conclusion, this one was definitely a contender. But he had one more skill on offer, and this one was legendary.

[Arcane Supremacy (Legendary)] – All other magic—all other energies—falter as you embrace the supremacy of your arcane affinity. Determined in your Path, you are ready to dedicate yourself to your arcane affinity once and for all. With conviction, reforge your body, making arcane energy more easily travel through your pathways while making you significantly more resilient to your own arcane energies. Passively increases the effectiveness and lowers the cost of all combat skills using arcane energy. As your bond with your arcane affinity deepens, so does your understanding of it, reducing the mana cost of all freeform manipulation using your arcane mana while increasing its power. As your arcane affinity strengthens, you surrender other forms of magic, significantly increasing the cost and lowering the effectiveness of all combat skills and freeform magic that does not utilize your arcane affinity.

When reading this skill, Jake was instantly reminded of Attunement skills. In prior skill selections, Jake had been offered both the Curse and Dark Attunement skills, which would have permanently transformed a portion of his energies into dark mana or curse energy, with the benefit of any magic using those energies improving, but at the cost of any other types of energy manipulation getting worse.

This one was incredibly similar to that, but it was no Attunement skill. Attunement skills were permanent changes to your status menu, literally adding or changing it to have a new resource. Arcane Supremacy, being a passive skill, would likely also lead to some changes, but it was far from as severe as an Attunement skill.

The biggest difference was that this one only really affected combat skills and magic. Wondering about something, Jake checked his status menu just to confirm. Yep, pretty much all his skills already integrated his arcane affinity in some way or another. The only ones he was a bit worried about were those like Steady Aim, Relentless Hunt, and especially Eternal Shadow… but he was unsure if those were even affected, or if they maybe somehow utilized his arcane affinity even if the descriptions didn’t clarify it. One had to remember that his arcane affinity came at least partly from his Bloodline, so any skill related to that should also be affected positively, right? Or at least not negatively impacted.

Even something like curse energy, Jake knew he could merge with his arcane affinity. In fact, it was better to merge it with his arcane affinity to stabilize it—something the Curse Fragments he had just learned to make were already doing. The Penetrating Stab also already used his arcane affinity.

One thing that also really interested him was how this one would work with Arcane Awakening. The part about making his body more resilient to his own arcane energies had to work great with his boosting skill, right? As it was his own affinity, Jake already had an insane innate resistance to arcane energy, but that didn’t mean he would say no to having to be even better.

Oh, yeah, and reading more closely, when it talked about freeform manipulation of arcane mana, it didn’t actually say that part only worked in combat… so maybe he could even use that elsewhere? The possibilities…

All in all, Jake concluded that Arcane Supremacy was a skill that would effectively buff nearly every aspect of combat, with minimal downsides, and those downsides could quickly be ironed out. The only true negative was that this would involve Jake fully dedicating himself to a Path. He would, once and for all, go all-in with his arcane affinity over all other types of energy. Which, to be fair, he was kind of already doing.

It was a good skill; no two ways about it. Legendary, too. Plus, it had a great name, in Jake’s opinion. The thing was, there were a lot of good offers this time around.

Jake read over the skills one more time, and he kind of liked the final three offerings. Arcane Arrow Rain of Horizon’s Edge, Penetrating Arcane Arrow of Horizon’s Edge, and Arcane Supremacy all had different pros and cons, but all shared that they would be great additions. One would make him far better against massive foes and large-scale combat, as well as just giving more overall damage to one of his core skills. Another would give him an arrow to break defenses and even empower his other, already massively powerful attacks, such as his Protean Arrow, while the final one would just make nearly everything Jake did slightly stronger.

So… which one should he pick?

Chapter 74

A Bit of Testing

Choosing skills was much easier when there were four shit options and only one skill he wanted. Numerous appealing options complicated this. If possible, he would have picked at least two of them, as he was honestly fine with missing out on either Penetrating Arcane Arrow or Arcane Arrow Rain, but he really wanted at least one of them.

That supercharging effect was just too damn interesting. What’s more, if it truly was something inherent to Jake’s class, would he maybe be able to upgrade other skills with the same effect? Would he be able to make an even better Protean Arrow that he could supercharge? Or, to be extreme… a supercharged Eternal Shadow?

Jake sucked at theoretical stuff, but as long as he felt how the supercharging effect worked just once, he would at least have an idea of how to apply it elsewhere.

But… if he wanted that, he would have to skip Arcane Supremacy. Just the name alone appealed to him, as his arcane affinity was indeed the supreme form of magic, but there were cons to picking it. Plus, he had no idea how it would interact with his Malefic Viper Legacy skills or his ability to easily use curse magic. Touch should be fine, as he had pretty good control over that one and could easily toss a bit of arcane affinity in there, but what about Scales? Wings? Fangs? Pride? All of them. Shit, just something like Malefic Viper’s Poison, which made all his poison better and not have anything to do with his arcane affinity. Would that somehow be negatively impacted, meaning all of his poisons would be worse?

Also, while Arcane Supremacy was cool, so was being able to supercharge skills.

Mentally, he had already written off Arcane Arrow Rain while just thinkings this over a bit more, and for two big reasons. One was that it just seemed the least interesting of the three, and two, it was an upgrade to an existing skill. That meant he could upgrade the skill himself, even if he couldn’t make it as good. Picking one of the other options would add a new skill, and Villy had repeatedly talked about how having more skills tended to be straight-up better.

Jake momentarily considered asking the Sword Saint or one of the others but decided against it. This was his skill selection and his Path. He had complained to the Sword Saint about the mythical Hallowed Shroud, but he hadn’t actually asked for advice, as he already knew such a skill didn’t fit him. If he didn’t know his own Path or what he wanted to do, how could he expect anyone else to?

Arcane Supremacy does seem best overall, right? he questioned. Yeah, it did. But picking it did mean fully committing to his arcane affinity, akin to picking an Attunement skill. He felt like there were many unknowns with doing that… and what if he discovered an affinity that he also wanted to use at some point? Curse energy wasn’t something he had initially been interested in, but now it was a core part of his Path. What if that happened with some magic affinity he just hadn’t encountered yet? What if there proved to be some fundamental problem with his arcane affinity? What if he faced an enemy who somehow resisted his arcane energy?

What if…

Fuck off, Jake… You gotta commit to things sometimes, he scolded himself as he got his shit together. Logically, he knew Arcane Supremacy was the best. He would have to dedicate himself at some point to an affinity, as not doing so was just leaving power on the table. His intuition was also telling him he bloody had to pick it, but he still felt damn insecure. He was bad at commitments and any skills that would “lock out” other options… but there were times one had to do that.

Jake’s arcane affinity was his affinity. There would never be any affinity that could suit him better, as this one was literally created by him and tied to who he was. If there was any type of magic or affinity to ever commit to, it would be his own. Even if some of his skills didn’t benefit from the focus or were negatively impacted right now, he would fix it in the future.

All he could hope was that the next skill selection didn’t have any interesting options, or at least had another skill with the supercharge option, because this time, it had to be Arcane Supremacy. With conviction, he selected the legendary skill.

*New skill gained*: [Arcane Supremacy (Legendary)]

He took a deep breath, as he felt something was coming. Seconds passed before a shiver went through his arms and slowly spread throughout the rest of his body. The shiver was slowly replaced by an odd, warm sensation that was on the brink of feeling painful, and in his sphere, he saw a bit of skin slowly beginning to peel.

Then the system truly went into gear. A protective bubble formed around Jake’s entire body, obscuring his form from the others waiting in the in-between room, as the reforging process began. His flaying sped up, both arms rapidly dissolving as if destructive arcane energy had ravaged them, yet the very next second, what had been destroyed was rebuilt.

This was not simply his physical body undergoing a metamorphosis, but his entire Soulshape. The countless pathways that transported innate energy—stamina—throughout his body expanded and changed; next, the veins responsible for health points—vital energy—underwent their own rebirth.

Nearly no part of Jake was left untouched. The only things the system didn’t influence were his eyes, as trying to reforge them was utterly unnecessary. However, he was surprised when he felt a faint spectral outline behind his back also being influenced—until he realized it was his Wings of the Malefic Viper. Even if he didn’t have them summoned now, Arcane Supremacy still affected them.

Jake had wondered if he could achieve something akin to what this skill did himself… but upon undergoing the reforging process, he became fully aware of how far he was from achieving something like that. The endless pathways making up the body were so numerous it didn’t make any sense, and each evolution only added more and changed those that were already there. To manually try to do something like this would be akin to changing a living being by going in and affecting every cell individually. Plus, one had to be able to make this change within a very short timeframe, or the body would be imbalanced and try to “heal” any damage inflicted. Not to mention the fact that one had to figure out a way to not just find and influence all of these pathways… but also do it in a way that could directly change the Soulshape.

Soon enough, the reforging approached its end. Jake had almost expected his Bloodline to act up or do something during all this, but it was surprisingly silent. Content. It clearly approved of what was happening, and as Jake began to inspect some of the changes, he couldn’t help but think…

This feels right… More right than it was before?

It was odd. The changed parts of Jake’s body felt more… natural? At least, more so than before being reforged. Like this was how they had always been supposed to look… No… maybe that it was at least closer to it than before? He couldn’t quite put his finger on it, and before he could properly get an idea, his metamorphosis was fully complete.

The entire process had only taken around a minute, and then the protective shell that had formed around him slowly disappeared. Jake opened his eyes to see four individuals staring down at him: Dina with a worried look, the Fallen King and Sword Saint with pure interest, and Sylphie like she was annoyed at his commotion waking her up.

“So… you got an interesting skill, I take it?” the Sword Saint asked with a raised eyebrow.

“It reminded me a bit of when I underwent my full Nature Attunement… but not quite?” Dina said, slightly confused.

“First of all, yes, very interesting, and it is pretty close to an Attunement skill, Dina,” Jake said, answering the both of them as he slowly opened and closed his hand.

“So, you have chosen to specialize your magic?” the Fallen King questioned.

“As I said, something like that,” Jake said as he let a spark of arcane energy jump between his index finger and thumb. “I guess you can say I finally committed properly to my own arcane affinity, as odd as that sounds.”

“Will it affect your alchemy skills?” Dina asked with a bit of worry. “More often than not, that is one of the big hurdles for Attunement skills, as they can create difficulties for crafting. As far as I know, most alchemy is best with pure, unattuned mana, so if you are attuned, it adds another layer of challenge and complexity.”

Jake transported some pure mana through his body to test it before shaking his head. “Nope, alchemy seems unaffected… In fact, it may be better than before. No problems moving pure mana around, at least.”

“Hm,” Dina said before smiling cheerfully. “Arcane affinities are odd, so I won’t ask anything. But it sounds like it was a good upgrade, so congratulations!”

“Thanks,” Jake said, smiling back at her. “Now, can I get a bit of time to familiarize myself with things?”

“How long will you need, you think?” the Sword Saint asked.

“Not long, I reckon. But don’t worry. I have a strong feeling I would like to do some live testing pretty soon.”

“Very well. Notify us when you are ready.” The old man then went over to a corner and sat down to meditate. The others also went back to doing their own thing, leaving Jake to his testing. As much testing as he could do in the relatively small in-between room, anyway.

Jake started by consciously moving some arcane energy around. The process was much smoother than before. It was like his internal channels had been slightly expanded and lubricated, at least when it came to leading arcane energy through his body. He also quickly tried summoning a bit of magic, starting with a barrier of stable arcane mana to encase himself, both as an experiment and to avoid annoying the others too much.

With little effort, arcane mana manifested all around him, forming a stable barrier in a bubble nearly instantly.

Faster than before, for sure… by around twenty percent, maybe?

Next, he took out Eternal Hunger and did a pressure test. He rested the tip on the barrier and slowly applied pressure until the arcane barrier began to crack and break. He repeated this a few more times as he kept summoning barriers to break.

Durability is up, too, and more than the summoning speed. Maybe thirty percent?

Jake did regret not doing all these tests before he picked the skill to have a better control group, but he’d luckily had a pretty good feeling about how strong his different skills and freeform magic had been before he got Arcane Supremacy.

Anyway, after a few more tests with both stable and destructive arcane mana using freeform magic, he concluded that both had undergone significant improvements. Summoning speed had improved the least, as Jake had already been pretty good at that before, but potency was where things had improved the most. For stable constructs, he had just gone over how much they improved, while for destructive energies, he summoned them about fifteen percent faster, and the potency had gone up about twenty-five percent. So, a bit less than the stable variant.

Due to Jake’s high Perception, he had always been pretty fast at summoning magic, so he guessed the bonus to that and potency were actually pretty similar. He also had more practice with destructive arcane energies, so he guessed the “true” bonus to summoning and potency—not factoring in his skill—was somewhere around twenty percent for both. In other words, this bonus made his arcane freeform magic twenty percent better under ideal circumstances while probably adding more under non-ideal circumstances.

Next up was the improvement seen with skills. That one proved to be a bit trickier to determine. Skills already included system assistance when activating them, and while you could practice and get better, you couldn’t do so as much as you could with freeform magic. This didn’t mean that skills didn’t benefit, though. Through a quick test, he noticed the charging speed of Arcane Powershot had gotten faster, and his ability to construct a Protean Arrow had definitely sped up.

Power-wise, he estimated the boost was a tad lower across the board and varied based on the skill. Something like his Avaricious Arcane Arrows—the arrows he normally shot—were, surprisingly enough, nearly twenty-five percent better than before, while the power of Arcane Powershot had only improved by about ten percent. Well, okay, that wasn’t entirely accurate, as his increased resistance also allowed him to now charge Arcane Powershot for longer and faster, resulting in that potentially being the skill that improved the most.

He also wanted to test Arcane Awakening but decided to wait with that, as he would rather see the effects in a real fight. Besides, he would probably piss off his party members if he decided to see how far he could push the skill while inside the in-between room, delaying their progress even more than necessary.

Finally, when it came to the increase in efficiency and reduced energy cost, Jake had to be honest and admit that part was by far the weakest aspect of the skill. It wasn’t really that he spent less mana doing stuff. It was just that less was lost in transportation, meaning he would estimate five to ten percent efficiency improvement at most across the board.

Now for the downsides of the upgrade.

First, Jake tried to move some dark mana through his veins to form a bolt of dark mana… and it was like dragging sludge. The feeling of the pathways being lubricated had turned from smoothing things out to now being a sticky substance that made everything harder.

Power, speed, and efficiency had all fallen even more than his arcane energy had improved. With a bit of worry, he tried to move curse energy next and found the same result. It was indeed a lot worse in every single way.

Trying again, Jake did the same test with dark mana, but this time sprinkled in a bit of stable arcane energy and found that the dark mana traveled through his body as if it was arcane energy. The bonus did seem slightly weaker, but it was there.

So, merging other affinities or types of magic with arcane energy works. Great.

Having tested that, Jake finally decided to try a few Malefic Viper Legacy skills… which he had been dreading. He hoped they wouldn’t have been impacted too badly and began by summoning Scales and Wings. Both appeared and…

Nothing.

It felt the exact same as before, with the cost and effectiveness both utterly unaffected. Confused as hell, he pulled out Eternal Hunger and infused it with venom from Fang… and once more, everything was the same. He kept trying, wondering what was going on, until a rush of realization hit him.

Villy, you glorious bastard, Jake thought, grinning widely.

Arcane Supremacy worked on combat skills and freeform magic.

All of the Legacy skills were technically not combat-related skills. Sure, they were used in combat, but they all had Origins in something alchemy-related, resulting in them not being considered combat skills by the system. Truly, Villy was truly a goddamn scammer.

Wait, does that mean…

Jake tried his new skill to summon Curse Fragments right then and there. He felt the curse energy moving through his pathways, unaffected. It was like the “lubricating” effect didn’t impact it at all. It wasn’t a combat skill, after all. This also meant that the arcane parts of the skill didn’t receive any benefits from Arcane Supremacy.

Next, he took out his cauldron and used brew potion real quick, once more noting it was unaffected. So that was a relief.

He kept trying a few more minor things but quickly reached a bit of an impasse. Any further testing he wanted would take too long or require real combat. That, or for him to at least not be locked in a small room where he couldn’t make big explosions or fully charge an Arcane Powershot without blowing up someone.

Standing up, Jake stretched. “Alright, gang, done testing and ready to go.”

It was time to experiment and get some floors done. Oh, and probably have some more multiversal lessons imparted to them.

Chapter 75

Two More Lessons Learned

Jake had a lot he wanted to test on the next floor, but sadly, he wasn’t really able to. At least, not right away.

The forty-third floor was indeed another “lesson” from the Wyrmgod, but this one wasn’t as much about any hard rules as it was about a norm and something that was generally frowned upon. It was a message that if they decided to act in a way that many wouldn’t find acceptable, they could put themselves in a bad situation and make enemies unintentionally.

When they appeared on floor forty-three, they were on board a spaceship traveling toward a large asteroid belt, where each asteroid may as well have been a small planet. The story was that they were mercenaries in a vessel stranded in space after a battle with space pirates—yes, there were pirates on this floor again—and during this fight, the ship had gotten damaged.

Their job was to scour this asteroid belt for natural treasures that could be used to repair the ship, but after they arrived, they discovered that dangerous, wanted people were also hiding out on these asteroids among the natives.

To further complicate things, these planets were filled to the brim with people of all sorts of races. Tens, if not hundreds of billions of humans, beastfolk, demons, monsters, elves, dwarves… All sorts of races lived on these asteroids, the most powerful of which was only in D-grade. Outside of the criminals, that is, all of whom were firmly in C-grade.

Calling them criminals was honestly a bit… wrong? They were people who had pissed off major factions in myriad ways, some of which Jake deemed legitimate, others bullshit. For example, one of the criminals had purposefully created cursed weapons and armor and spread them to unsuspecting people, driving them insane and wiping out a huge kingdom by proxy. That guy was clearly an asshole, and Jake was fine with stomping him.

However, there were also cases where the big bad criminal had done some rather basic stuff, just to the wrong people. One of them had killed someone with a Divine Blessing in self-defense and was now marked as a heretic to be hunted down and killed on sight, and another had taken and consumed a natural treasure some kingdom totally had their eyes on first.

Now, this is where a bit of important context should be added… The spaceship wasn’t really one made for C-grades. In fact, the being controlling it was a mid-tier B-grade automata that had merged itself with the ship. Despite being damaged, it could still harness the full weapons system of the ship.

This is to say, it had the ability to blow up smaller planets, or at least these asteroids.

The B-grade automata captain instantly decided that they should also investigate and eliminate the criminals, along with retrieving the items needed to repair the ship. Luckily, they didn’t have to fully search the asteroids, as the ship had a mobile scanner they could bring with them when going down on each asteroid.

So, to fully summarize, Jake and company had the job of investigating the asteroids for treasures to repair the ship using a scanner while at the same time identifying the C-grade criminals hidden there and eliminating them all. Locating these criminals was the hard part, and all they had to do to beat the floor was collect the treasures. It wouldn’t take more than a few days to figure out whether each planet had any treasures.

Once it was determined that there were no treasures, they could then decide to go back to the ship… and, to “optimize” their points per day, do a little bit of lying by telling the automata that the asteroid was filled with really bad criminals and thus needed to be blown up. That way, they could kill all the criminals there without bothering to find each one individually, only at the sacrifice of a few billion F-, E-, and D-grades.

This was one part of the moral lesson. Because while it was made clear that this was an option, it was also made clear this could be frowned upon. Killing billions to just take out a handful of potential targets wasn’t something any laws directly prohibited, but doing so wasn’t exactly looked upon kindly either.

Not to say that actually eliminating the criminals on the asteroids was simple if one wanted to avoid collateral damage, even after they had identified them. A genius-level C-grade and a mid-tier C-grade fighting could wreak a lot of damage—something Jake had been a witness to during his visions of the Malefic Viper—so deciding to kill them also had to be done with caution to avoid widespread destruction.

The reason wholesale slaughter of the “weak” was so frowned upon wasn’t entirely due to some altruistic intent from the multiverse’s major factions. Sure, there probably was a touch of moral thinking in there somewhere, but one of the predominant reasons was the fear of setting a precedent.

If one faction decided to send a group of C-grades to destroy a few small planets belonging to a major faction, chances were the faction would retaliate in kind, but with more force to not appear weak. So they would send a few B-grades and blow up even more planets… only for the first faction to then send A-grades… and finally, a bunch of gods would be going around, wiping out all life in galaxies. This kind of “war” would have no end and only lead to the ruination of a faction’s future.

No, it was instead far more accepted to just send the first group of C-grades after another group of C-grades. Then they could fight, and the only “fair” retaliation would be something similar, making it far less of a slaughter and more like a competition. It also meant that the higher-ups wouldn’t move, as that would ultimately make them look like the true aggressors by escalating the conflict.

This was also viewed as safer. In Villy’s words, most gods or even just very high-grade people were fucking cowards. They didn’t dare fight others around their own level of power, instead preferring to settle matters through proxies. Rather than two gods fighting, they would compete in some other fashion, like setting up a tournament with A-grades or a war with C-grades, all while setting rules to make it a “fair” fight. This also had the benefit of assisting the people made to take part in these competitions, effectively cultivating the next generation.

Killing a random planet of D-grades could also have other unwanted implications. Karma was a powerful thing, and no one knew whether some random A-grade had once been born there, or if some god had taken a liking to it a few millennia earlier, thus experiencing annoyance at the decision to blow it up.

The spaceship had records of some such incidents that they could freely listen to while traveling between asteroids. One of the examples that struck Jake was about a late-tier god who had arrived on a planet and really liked a certain lake. He had settled down there for a long time and meditated, finally breaking free from his worries to pass the final step and become a Godking. Two thousand years later, two S-grades were fighting and ended up accidentally destroying the planet, resulting in the Godking descending in the middle of the fight to destroy both of them for their transgression. He had then proceeded to wipe out both factions the S-grades were leaders of for good measure to quell his anger.

All because they had ruined a nice lakeside view.

To summarize, killing innocent people shouldn’t be done haphazardly, or you could piss someone off unintentionally. That, and it was just a bad look.

Anyway, when doing the floor, they didn’t blow up any asteroids. No, they were more than overpowered enough by themselves to utterly cheese the floors. Jake had his wonderful Pulse of Perception and a powerful innate Bloodline-powered ability to sense auras, allowing him to know if an asteroid had any C-grades pretty damn quickly after stepping foot on one.

Not that he was the most overpowered of them. You see, planets filled with enlightened beings and beasts were naturally full of life. Life meant plants. Plants meant Dina could also ask a damn forest that had existed for tens of thousands of years about stuff, and it would know, while sometimes even asking its friends, resulting in their fastest asteroid clearing—including getting a natural treasure—being less than half an hour.

This all resulted in them going through nearly a hundred and fifty asteroids with life in only seven months, with the majority of the time spent flying between each of them. Jake got some good alchemy done during this time and gleefully experimented with Curse Fragments whenever they had downtime. Sadly, there wasn’t a single time he had to go all-out during the entire floor, as the one time they did find a small asteroid just filled with criminals, Jake and Dina had already been sent off to two other asteroids nearby. The Fallen King, Sylphie, and Sword Saint had thus been the only ones to experience proper combat, spending a week or so killing all the leaders of some criminal gang that had taken over the asteroid while also retrieving the final item they needed to repair the ship and move on to the next floor.

Thus, they pretty easily did floor forty-three while learning the lesson that going full murderhobo on a bunch of E- and D-grades wasn’t cool.

Regarding floor forty-four, Jake honestly hadn’t known what to expect. What more rules and norms were there?

Well, floor forty-four ended up feeling kind of… personal for Jake. For many of them, actually.

Because while floor forty-three had been about how valued large groups of weaker people were, and how one should leave them alone as a general rule, floor forty-four was all about individual creatures one should leave the hell alone.

They had appeared on what looked like a massive disc floating through space, filled with a spread of large islands—both below and on the water, and floating up in the sky. Each island had its own little ecosystem and was covered by some kind of barrier keeping all the creatures inside. New monster variants had begun appearing within these domes, with their floor-clearing quest asking them to find and identify at least two hundred and fifty variants worth noting.

Information was pretty scarce, but the one that tasked them with this quest was an old woman living in a hut. She was Identified as a level 250 Researcher but, based on Jake’s senses, was actually far more powerful than that. Not quite a god, but definitely A-grade. None of the others could notice this, though Sylphie did talk about how the wind avoided her, which made her think something was wrong.

Anyway, they were to find these rare variants and then categorize where they were, all without directly engaging them in combat. The lesson from the Researcher was that all variants were of value to the multiverse, as they represented new and growing Records. A single powerful variant appearing on a planet—or a dome, in this case—could uplift the entire ecosystem and lead to a cascade effect.

It was a bit like what had happened with Earth, partly because of Jake. So many powerful people appearing there had resulted in massive growth potential, even for the average Earthling. People who previously could never have reached C-grade had now set foot in the grade, and those who likely could have gotten there themselves now had far better evolutions and future prospects.

Variants appearing also mattered to many factions due to the potential of allying with them. Two variants of a similar species having a child would lead to a merge of their Records, and sometimes a more powerful variant than both of them would emerge. Adding new variants thus mattered a lot to some factions, even to the gods. This was naturally something Jake was very well aware of, considering his status as a so-called “Harbinger of Primeval Origins.”

On that note, no, Jake didn’t even consider for a second trying to get extra points or achievements by making a variant on floor forty-four. The Primal Juice or whatever was far too valuable and not something to squirt out haphazardly.

Anyway, all of this is to say that a lot of factions would get royally pissed if someone went around killing weak variants for no reason. It was generally considered customary that if you, as a C-grade, saw a lower-grade variant running around, you would leave it alone. If you did want to get rid of it, you could always just send someone around their own level, at least allowing the person who killed it to get something out of the entire thing.

So, the entire floor was basically flying between massive domes all over ten thousand kilometers in diameter, categorizing variants, and taking notes, with the Researcher then deciding if the observed beast or monster was considered rare enough to count.

Well, that, or just killing them outright, no matter their grade.

Because the lesson of this floor wasn’t just to respect variants and the Records they represented, but to be aware that some creature variants were to be killed on sight. These types of creatures were often considered living calamities.

Curse Remnants.

Plague Spirits.

And… one Jake truly did agree was a menace to the entire multiverse: fungi.

Or, well, not necessarily just fungi or all kinds of fungi. In general, plant-based living creatures with Truesouls weren’t really that special. The tree Jake had met in the center of the forest close to Haven was a common example of a plant monster, and so was the fungal colony Jake had seen below Haven. But one of them was viewed far less favorably than the others.

Fungi that could infect other plant life were often seen as a pest akin to an ectognamorph hive but were not really viewed as calamities. Still, some variants that didn’t just absorb energy from and control plant life could appear. Some evolved to control any form of life, or even anything with a soul or energy. These fungi or plants could evolve to take over entire planets, creating massive bodies out of them. From there, they would then spread and try to consume other planets one after another until they were killed or died due to age.

These plant and fungi monsters, in that sense, weren’t that distinct from the aforementioned ectognamorphs, but there was one big difference: sapience. A hive could be talked to. Negotiated with. They could join a faction. These plants nearly never had any true intelligence, not even when reaching S-grade. Only if they somehow managed to become gods would they truly awaken.

Plague Spirits and such were much the same, in that they only had an instinct. Curse Remnants also only existed to do whatever the curse represented, which was rarely something pleasant.

The final kind of creature one was meant to at least consider killing on sight was one familiar to Jake: Monsters that had lost themselves and had become living killing machines that destroyed anything they came across without a care in the world.

Prime example? C- and especially B-grade Villy. He had been a bloody menace back then, wiping out all life on his own birth planet before proceeding to slaughter whatever else he came across. Based on what Jake had seen, this had only happened in late-tier C-grade for Villy, though. Jake was unsure what exactly had happened between the Villy he’d seen being crafty with the First Sage and fooling human kingdoms, to the Villy that had sat in wyvern form on top of a cliff, roaring toward the sky. B-grade Villy had been bad all the way through; no two ways about it.

Naturally, no powerful A- or S-grade had killed Villy during his rise to power, and Jake was thankful for that. As for now… no one would even talk negatively about this. This was a great example of why these weren’t really hard rules. Though, to be fair, there weren’t truly any hard rules in the multiverse.

Plagues were not looked upon nicely, and some types were viewed as outlawed, yet Jake knew the Order still worked on them. One was not meant to mess with random weak people, yet Eversmile still did experiments that doomed entire civilizations without a care in the world, while Stormild could casually consume an entire galaxy indiscriminately. Yet none looked at the Primordials and called them criminals. These were ultimately just outlines of what one could expect to piss off other factions by doing, but as long as you had the backing or the power, it didn’t truly matter. Shit, based on some of the things mentioned, Jake and Eternal Hunger broke quite a few norms and rules.

Back to floor forty-four… This one wasn’t hard either. It was all about exploration like the prior floor while having the Researcher tell them about how important rare variants were to the balance of the multiverse. This one was better, though, as there was a bit more combat, and they didn’t have to rely on a spaceship to take them around, allowing them to beat the floor in “just” five months. Pretty good for these larger floors.

After reporting on variants one final time, the Researcher summoned a portal, as “new assistants were arriving shortly to replace them,” and thanked them for their contribution. Another floor down.

Floors forty-three and forty-four had both been pretty simple and not that difficult, even allowing them to rack up plenty of bonus points by doing things fast and well. Things had been pretty straightforward, and they had done as expected with great results. However, the last of these “laws and norms” floors, as Jake dubbed them, would prove to be a touch more… complicated. Because this one was all about a rule in the multiverse Jake was really, really bad at:

Respecting divine authority.

Chapter 76

To Respect Divine Authority

Another in-between room, another small break before it was on to floor forty-five.

Over a year had passed since Jake had gotten his Arcane Supremacy skill, and throughout this time, he’d been able to thoroughly familiarize himself with the skill. He’d had time to relearn some things about his own body and truly discover how massive the bonus from the skill had been, despite the less-than-optimal setup of the floors he had been through.

The two skills that benefitted the most turned out to be Arcane Awakening, which wasn’t overly surprising, and Arcane Powershot, which did somewhat surprise him. Pure arcane magic benefitted the most, but something like Arcane Powershot dipped into several concepts along with the purely physical aspects.

Arcane Awakening, on the other hand, dipped into all of the benefits provided by Arcane Supremacy. The lowered cost naturally made the skill more efficient, and the increased potency materialized in Jake needing to move less energy through his body to achieve the same effect as before, thus also lessening the strain on his body and increasing the time he could keep the skill active.

Adding on his increased resistance to his own arcane energy, the benefit was massive. He could now keep the stable 30% boost active nearly indefinitely without suffering much strain on his body, while the offensive and defensive modes were also pretty easy to deal with. He wouldn’t even suffer any period of weakness from using these two anymore, as long as he didn’t use them for a prolonged period.

A full Arcane Awakening boosting all his stats by 60% still took a lot out of him, and getting around the period of weakness wasn’t going to happen. It wasn’t as bad as before, though, and he could keep the full boost active for longer, especially since the health drain had been reduced significantly. The passive shield and extra arcane damage with every attack had naturally also both been improved.

Arcane Awakening still didn’t allow him to boost above the percentages set by the skill without him deciding to purposefully push it higher, which was something he hadn’t dared to do lest he blow himself up. Even if Arcane Supremacy had given him more control over his energies, he still doubted he would get out of doing that unscathed, assuming he survived it at all. But… the potential for doing so was definitely there. Circumstances would decide if he would ever do it.

The second skill that had experienced massive benefits was, as mentioned, Arcane Powershot, and some of the benefits were for quite obvious reasons. He could charge it faster and for longer due to his increased control and resistance, respectively, and release far more potent shots due to everything put together. Since the skill wasn’t only about arcane energy, it “only” got around thirty percent better in total… but adding thirty percent extra power to his most reliable attack? Yeah, that was massive.

However… Jake did find one skill that had gotten worse, and he had no idea how to fix it. One Step had been hit quite hard by the increased resource cost, which was a real bummer, as he quite frankly had no bloody idea how to integrate his arcane energy into that skill. It was a well-defined Legacy skill, so even if he wanted an upgrade, it definitely wasn’t going to be easy. Shit, if he broke the set upgrade path, it would only get harder to upgrade it in the future… so as things were now, this was just a loss he would have to live with. It wasn’t all bad, though.

The one good thing was that the increased stamina cost was only an issue in combat. When Jake used it just as a skill to travel, the cost remained unaffected, which he assumed was due to the skill being originally invented as a traveling skill, not a combat skill. He was also very happy that the system distinguishing whether or not a skill was used in combat wasn’t being applied to the Malefic Viper Legacy skills.

Oh, and there was one other skill that had been negatively affected… though that hadn’t been for long. Jake was naturally talking about Splitting Arrow Rain, which was upgraded pretty damn quickly with inspiration from his skill selection.

[Splitting Arrow Rain (Rare)] – A skill most often used by archers, now usurped and reformed by the Avaricious Arcane Hunter. Allows you to clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties. Each arrow has variable strength and can be further split into less potent versions. If the original arrow is shot upwards, it can be split to create a far more potent arrow rain. Adds a small bonus to the effect of Agility and Wisdom when using Splitting Arrow Rain. Increased damage based on Perception and the distance the arrows fall from when creating an arrow rain.

-->

[Splitting Arcane Arrow Rain (Epic)] – A skill most often used by archers, now usurped and reformed by the Arcane Hunter of Horizon's Edge. Allows you to clone your arrows while in flight, allowing them to retain innate magical properties. Each arrow has variable strength and can be further split into less potent versions. If the original arrow is shot upwards, you can explode hundreds of smaller arrows, creating an Arcane Arrow Rain. Cloning arcane arrows or creating Arcane Arrow Rains using arcane arrows has a far lower mana and stamina cost. Adds a bonus to the effectiveness of Agility and Wisdom when using Arcane Arrow Rain. Increased damage based on Perception and the distance the arrows fall from when creating an Arcane Arrow Rain.

The skill honestly just integrated what he could get from the better Arrow Rain in the skill selection. It now used arcane energy, allowing him to clone arrows more cheaply while also adding on the part where he exploded an arrow to make it rain. That was definitely better than what he’d done before, where he just shot upward and waited for the arrow to begin falling downward on its own.

He also finally got working on some curse-based poison, but it proved a lot more difficult than he had thought it would, so progress was slow in that department. Overall, things felt pretty slow, considering that even after two more floors, Jake had barely gotten any levels.

Status

Name: Jake Thayne

Race: [Human (C) – lvl 232]

Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge – lvl 232]

Profession: [Heretic-Chosen Alchemist of the Malefic Viper – lvl 233]

Two class levels and three profession levels were all two floors and just over a year amounted to. By now, Jake had been forced to get used to slower levels unless he did something truly impressive. He kind of wished he could do a Minaga fight every floor, but alas, that wasn’t how Nevermore worked. Or anything worked, really.

How it did work was by throwing them on another floor meant to teach them a lesson. And the old man already had a good guess regarding what the last “lesson” floor would be about before they entered it.

“It will be related to gods and religion in some way,” the Sword Saint said with certainty as they were about to exit the in-between room.

“That… can either go very well or really badly,” Jake muttered. “Assuming you are right, that is.”

He was right.

Stepping through the gateway, they appeared in the middle of a town square in what seemed to be the middle of the night. The place was pretty damn deserted, with many old, medieval-looking buildings surrounding them. The only place with bustling activity was a massive church at the end of the square, and through a quick pulse, Jake saw the place was jam-packed. Tens of thousands were within, praying.

Fuck me, Jake cursed as the welcome message appeared.

Welcome to the forty-fifth floor of Nevermore: Peerin Kingdom of the Starcross Pantheon

You have stepped onto a planet owned by the Peerin Kingdom of the Starcross Pantheon, a powerful Pantheon ruled by over a dozen gods. The kingdom you have appeared in has been derelict for a long time, with no hopeful prospects appearing for over a thousand years, making it fall out of favor with the Pantheon.

As newcomers, you are unknown entities to the planet and must establish yourselves. Gain favor and recognition to gain access to the features of the kingdom as you aim to leave the floor and proceed to the next. Luckily, you have a token that will allow you to teleport to the next floor. There is just one problem.

The entirety of Peerin Kingdom falls within the protective formation laid down by the Starcross Pantheon, blocking all kinds of teleportation that take one outside of it. The only way off the floor is by leaving this formation first. You must navigate the kingdom and reach the waygate station at the edge of the kingdom, which will allow you to fully leave the Starcross Pantheon’s territory and, thus, the floor through the use of the token.

However, these teleportation circles are not available to the public and require permission to use. With B- and even A-grades present in the kingdom, trying to force your way through seems ill-advised.

No matter how you wish to approach this, getting the attention of the clergy will be vital to your mission, as they can either help or hinder you on your path, for they control the entire kingdom.

Main objective: Use the teleportation token to proceed to the next floor.

Bonus objectives: Get the attention of the clergy of the Peerin Kingdom (0/1)

Current progress: Token used (0/1), get the attention of the clergy of the Peerin Kingdom (0/1)

Note: More events, achievements, or objectives may be hidden on the floor.

Current Nevermore Points: 102,073

Right as Jake scanned the message, an odd emblem teleported right between the five of them. It didn’t take a genius to figure out this was the teleportation token, and Dina instantly grabbed it, being the designated “taker of mandatory items.”

“So…” Jake muttered as he scratched the back of his head.

“Firstly, we need to ensure the little hunter doesn’t instantly anger the clergy and get us all killed,” the Fallen King said.

“Seems like a good start… Sylphie should also be careful.” The Sword Saint smiled, getting an annoyed screech from the hawk. “Dina, would it be best if the two of us took the lead? I am sure you have plenty of experience with how one is supposed to act around religious figures, while I myself have had some unpleasant experiences with a certain god and am fully aware of how… demanding people of worship can be.”

Dina thought for a second before speaking. “Do we care about the bonus objectives here much? Or would it not be better to move on as fast as possible?”

A total no-brainer.

“Swift progress is preferred,” the Fallen King said.

“Ree.”

“Better to finish it quickly,” the old man put in, unsure what she was getting at.

Jake took his time, not answering until he understood. “I take it you also wanna just move on quickly?”

“Yes,” Dina said. “That should be more efficient.”

It was a bit absurd, but the last four floors since the Minaga fight had nearly doubled their total points. Jake and company had known that points would increase as one got further in Nevermore, but they hadn’t expected every single floor after floor forty to each give over 10,000 Nevermore Points. Especially considering that they didn’t even go insanely out of their way to do all the bonus objectives and achievements. But… just the huge floor-clear bonus being more than four thousand for each floor meant the gains were massive.

So, if they could pass the floor quickly and get 4500 Nevermore Points, that would likely give the best overall gain. Later floors just gave that many more points.

“I assume you have already felt it up ahead?” Dina continued. “There are many blessed inside… so I think it is worth a try.”

The Fallen King and Sword Saint also seemed to realize what the two of them were getting at, and the old man chuckled. “Sure, give it a go… If the floor blocks others from feeling Blessings, we can just do it the usual way.”

“And if they can feel Blessings?” Jake grinned.

“May the young master have whatever he pleases,” the Sword Saint said cheekily.

“Roger that,” Jake said as he stepped toward the church with the others in tow. They had to walk up nearly fifty steps to reach the giant, closed double door leading into the church proper, but about halfway up, Jake let it rip.

An aura blasted out of his body as Shroud of the Primordial fell away, and then he purposefully amplified his presence. It spread out of him… and less than a second later, the giant double doors slammed open, someone inside having felt Jake.

Felt his presence.

A few seconds later, a priest flanked by two paladins appeared at the top of the steps. He stared down at Jake and the three with him in confusion.

[Starcross Priest – lvl 280]

[Starcross Paladin – lvl 285]

[Starcross Paladin – lvl 282]

“I… Who are yo—”

“Call your god down here,” Jake interrupted.

“What?” the priest said, looking confused before suddenly turning angry. “How dare yo—”

“I wasn’t asking,” Jake said as he flared his aura even more, mixing in Pride of the Malefic Viper to further amplify it.

“And unless you want to create trouble for the Starcross Pantheon by ignoring the Chosen of a Primordial, I would very much comply,” the Sword Saint added, also tossing in a bit of his own aura as someone with a Divine Blessing from another Primordial.

Dina and Sylphie also joined in as the priest stared, clearly unsure how to react. When the two paladins moved forward in a defensive manner, Jake just sighed.

Very well… full young master mode engaged.

“I gave you a fucking order, so stop standing there like a moron and contact your god,” Jake said, scoffing. “Or are you some damn heretic? Is that why this pathetic kingdom has fallen into shambles?”

Jake wasn’t sure what more he could say, yet he soon discovered that the priest had indeed contacted someone. An aura appeared toward the back of the large church, and a second later, a figure teleported out to stand between Jake and the priest. Instantly, Jake became aware… A-grade.

But… he was in young master mode.

“What is going on he—”

“Fucking finally,” Jake said, sighing loudly. “Hey, you, are you as useless as this priest, or can you get your shit together and contact that Pantheon of yours already? I haven’t got all day.”

The A-grade looked at him and his companions for a moment before suddenly falling to his knees. “I greet the Chosen.”

Alright, seems like we are getting somewhere.

“Yeah, yeah, just contact the Pantheon. I would prefer to converse with someone possessing a worthy status.”

“Naturally,” the A-grade said as he put his hands together. His body glowed with divine light for a moment before he stood, still keeping his back bowed. “They will arrive shortly. I apologize for the disrespect and will make sure to right any injustices.”

The priest and paladins looked pretty damn frightened by now, but before they could do anything, the A-grade pointed at them and shot a beam into them, making them freeze and fall to the ground. “I shall remove these heretics from your sight at once.”

Jake thought he was overdoing it a little… but he was in young master mode. Still, he’d feel bad if they were punished for something he did.

“You only got yourself to blame for not properly teaching your clergy about proper procedures when it comes to meeting the Chosen of a Primordial.” Jake scoffed. “Now begone. You have done as I asked, and you are no longer of any use or concern.”

The A-grade didn’t even speak, just bowing deeply once more before teleporting away with the priest and paladins.

“That went well?” the Sword Saint said uncertainly through the mark.

“I think so; let’s just ho—”

Before Jake could even answer, a presence washed over the entire town. It utterly suppressed everything else, and Jake felt everything warp. Out of the corner of his eyes, he saw a flickering torch suddenly slow down its flickering and then stop completely. The feeling reminded him of the tutorial, when Eversmile had stopped time… because that was exactly what had happened.

Two figures appeared in the air, floating above them. A man and a woman, both with bluish skin and eyes reminding Jake of a starlit sky. They looked nearly identical, except for the difference in gender, though both were rather androgynous.

“What era are we in?” the male god asked as his eyes landed on Jake. “The Chosen of the Malefic Viper… Never did I think I would see the day a new one would appear.”

“Ninety-Third Era,” Jake answered. “Not long since the integration, considering I am a Progenitor along with being a Chosen.”

“Truly?” the male god said, then nodded. “How surprising, but not a thoroughly unpleasant piece of news.”

“Quite the party, too,” the woman spoke. “A Unique Lifeform, a relative of the Nature’s Attendant, and two individuals carrying the Divine Blessings of Stormild and Aeon.”

“The one blessed by Aeon is also a Transcendent,” the male god said, smiling.

“Oh, my,” the female god said in an impressed tone.

Both gods had floated down by now and landed in front of Jake and the others. Once more, the Sword Saint, Dina, and Fallen King felt the pressure, while Jake stood unaffected, an unbothered Sylphie perched on his shoulder.

“Entirely immune to the auras of gods?” the male god said, looking even more at Jake. “I am curious, but asking wouldn’t do me any good.”

Jake nodded. “Yeah, images in Nevermore and all that.”

“Indeed, it is so.” He smiled again. “I am glad to see that the Malefic One has returned to the multiverse, and you must give him our greetings once you are done in Nevermore. Just say the Starcrossed Twins send their regards.”

“I will keep that in mind.” Jake nodded, but chances were he was going to forget that.

“Now, let’s get on with why we are here,” the female god said. “This floor was made to teach the masses to respect divine authority, and… Hm, there is no need to explain, now, is there? As the Chosen, you are a living symbol of a Primordial's divine authority.” She giggled. “We shall not hold you more. Ah, but do take this.”

She tossed a small coin to Jake, which he instantly caught.

“If you ever feel like visiting the Starcross Pantheon’s territory in the true multiverse, you would be more than welcome, and that token should help you,” she said with a smile. “Now, let’s get this silly barrier down.” She reached out and took the hand of the male god, and both glowed with starlight for a second. She then let go and looked at Jake and the others. “We wish you godspeed on your continued descent of Nevermore.”

“Thanks, from all of us.” Jake smiled as he looked at Dina, who took out the teleportation token.

Floor forty-five?

Easiest floor of his life.

Chapter 77

Definitely Balanced

“Okay, not gonna lie, that was kind of hilarious,” Minaga said, chuckling after seeing Jake pass floor forty-five so easily. “Really just tossed his weight around and got all those poor suckers to get him out of there right away. They didn’t show it, but those Starcrossed Twins were pretty damn submissive compared to how they usually are.”

“I am surprised you got those two in here for such a floor,” Vilastromoz said with genuine confusion. “Any god would do, so why have two gods as old and powerful as them? That couldn’t have been easy.”

The Wyrmgod just sighed. “I had my reasons.”

Minaga raised a hand. “I know the reasons.”

Vilastromoz smiled and looked at the Wyrmgod, who reluctantly explained, “The origin of the images of mortals don’t truly matter that much, as before any of them are ever used, the mortal will more than likely already be dead. Things are different for gods. While nothing that happens to the image affects them, and they never become aware of any interactions these images had, there can still be consequences. For the gods, that is.”

The Viper suddenly understood, and he nodded while the Wyrmgod kept explaining. A bit needlessly, perhaps, but the old dragon did like to talk about his work when given the chance.

“There was an incident a few eras ago where the image of a god thoroughly pissed off a Chosen belonging to the Altmar Empire, to the point of just airing out his grievances that had arisen due to prior conflicts that the Altmar Empire thought they were over. While the god wasn’t able to hinder the Nevermore participant—nor did they make any attempts to—the Chosen still left deeply offended, and it turned into quite a situation. This resulted in all the images of gods from the Nevermore of the next era being far too… meek. Any time a Chosen or even someone with a Divine Blessing from a powerful god appeared, they would capitulate and pop in to help them right away with the hope of forming a good relationship with the young, influential C-grades and allowing them to effectively skip the floor. Needless to say, this went directly against the purpose of the floor.”

“So he thought up a great solution,” Minaga said, grinning.

“The thought process was to put gods here that wouldn’t feel the need to try to gain favor with even the Chosens of high-level gods, thus treating them like any other regular Nevermore participant,” the Wyrmgod said, rather annoyed. “The Starcrossed Twins are part of a powerful alliance already and are not people even pinnacle factions would create trouble with, meaning they didn’t have to act courteously and respect the status of any C-grades.”

“Yeah, brilliant thinking, and it worked out perfectly,” Minaga said, holding back a giggle. “Poor Jake had a horrible time in there.”

“The reappearance of the Malefic Viper, and the fact that he opted to have a C-grade Chosen, were unexpected factors, and I cannot blame them for making an exception. Also, it wasn’t as if I viewed it as an impossible outcome, seeing as I had already created an achievement for the feat.” The Wyrmgod didn’t seem interested in discussing the floor more.

“It’s a shame, though,” Minaga said. “Pretty sure that of everyone doing Nevermore, Jake is the one who needs to learn how to respect divine authority the most.” Clearly, he was not as happy to just drop the topic as the Wyrmgod.

“Or, have you considered that he is the only one showing the proper level of reverence towards other gods as my Chosen?” the Viper countered. “My Chosen being all subservient in front of other gods would be a bad look, you know? I never really thought about it before, but having a Chosen that isn’t naturally suppressed is quite nice.”

“You know, the way you phrased that makes it sound like he is subservient only to you as his Patron,” Minaga said. “And I somehow have a hard time believing that.”

“Oh, he is showing plenty of reverence. Jake is just the kind of guy that is all about action instead of petty words or platitudes.” Vilastromoz smiled. “I just view it as, every level he gains and every feat he accomplishes it partly in my name.”

“If that helps you meditate in peace,” Minaga said skeptically.

“His relatively selfish actions make me question that claim… though I reckon that if he proceeds on his Path as things are now, he will be a good return on investment simply due to the Records he obtains,” the Wyrmgod added. “Perhaps I should get a Chosen myself, though finding a good prospect is quite difficult.”

Vilastromoz nodded but didn’t elaborate. It was tempting to reveal that he had already gotten his return on investment simply through Jake’s action of consciously creating the Vespernat Hive Queen. That feat had even led to a cascade effect of Records from all his prior creations.

“Finding a good Chosen can indeed be a struggle, but if I find someone worth referring to you, I will let you know,” Vilastromoz said to his fellow Primordial. “If not, then at least someone to give a Divine Blessing.”

“Perhaps,” the Wyrmgod said with little commitment. “I wonder, will your Chosen be capable of influencing the birth of another creature like the Vespernat Hive Queen anytime soon? Assuming it is indeed a replicable act. That seems like a potential avenue to secure a good prospect.”

“I can’t answer that. You will have to ask Jake directly. I already told you and everyone else that the ability belongs to him and not me.” The Viper shook his head. “And I am a snake of my word.”

The Wyrmgod looked to be in for thought for a moment before simply nodding. “If that is how you wish to do things, fine. I am beginning to understand you have adopted an unconventional relationship with your Chosen, and I will not interfere in whatever you are planning.”

The Malefic Viper smiled. “Who says I am planning anything?”

Minaga and Wyrmgod just looked at him for a while before Minaga shrugged. “Yeah, true, you are the straightest of straight shooters, never done anything shady or had any underhanded plots or plans. Anyway, I sure hope you make it out of your conflict with Yip of Yore, because if you don’t have a plan, things are looking bleak.”

“Who knows?” Vilastromoz said, smiling.

“You do, and I wanna know.”

“It is not odd to want things you cannot have,” the Viper said evasively, his look of amusement growing. “In fact, isn’t that what brought us all to godhood? Trying to obtain the impossible?”

“Well, I am the curious sort. You know that. And I like to try and figure out things on my own when people aren’t telling me the whole truth.” Minaga now smiled in response, giving Vilastromoz a bad premonition. “Which reminds me… That Vesperia lady is real nice, though I can’t quite see the resemblance between her and her dad… Oh, sorry, I meant Sire.”

And this was why catching the curiosity of a god with a legion of clones, insatiable curiosity, and limitless time could be problematic.

Vesperia felt the strain on her soul, sensing she had reached her limit when it came to absorbing energy from the Hive Core. Absorbing the energies and Records of old was far from easy, and the toll was substantial. However, she had already exceeded all expectations and gotten further than any of her sisters had ever predicted she would. It had only taken her a few months, and yet she still wasn’t fully satiated.

Opening her eyes, the diadem atop her head shone with golden lights, as she had once more reached a new threshold. She felt the power rushing through her body, and she knew she had finally stepped into mid-tier C-grade. Opening her status, she saw that was indeed the case.

Status

Name: Vesperia

Race: [Vespernat Hive Queen – lvl 252]

Health Points (HP): 409,000/409,000

Mana Points (MP): 59,842/60,850

Stamina: 95,743/100,600

Hive Energy: 24,600/25,200

Her health had grown more than before, naturally empowered by her racial skills. She knew that humans were simple and only received 10 mana per Wisdom or 10 health per Vitality, but monsters weren’t like that. There were too many passives to easily compare, and her health pool, which would be considered ludicrous by the standards of enlightened species, was only regarded as high rather than top-tier amongst monsters.

When it came to Hive Energy, she had barely used any. It was not a resource one spent like normal and then replenished; every point spent was a point lost unless the being you spent it on disappeared. Vesperia herself had only made some eggs so far while familiarizing herself with her innate power.

As she was sitting there and getting her bearings, she got a notification informing her she had a visitor.

The chambers she had been given were on a planet only slightly smaller than the planet her Sire had been born on, and it was a nice place to do some experiments while still in C-grade. The entire place was also enforced with the protective formations of more than a dozen True Royals who’d ascended above the rank of Godqueen and been placed in the very heartlands of the Endless Empire.

This piece of information was important… because when she checked the projection of who had come to visit, she saw the Odonstrom Hive Queen together with an odd creature she didn’t quite recognize. It looked humanoid but had four eyes and blue skin. Based on how they stood together, Vesperia assumed he was a god, and seeing no reason to reject them, she welcomed them inside. She also knew that any being that could walk into the heartlands of the Endless Empire like this was someone she had to wary of.

A second later, both figures teleported into the welcome hall that had already been set up a long time ago by the other ectognamorphs that served her.

“I apologize for the sudden visit, Sister,” the Odonstrom True Royal said, smiling.

“Hey-o, I’m Minaga—nice to meet you!” the blue four-eyed god added, also smiling.

Vesperia was a bit taken aback by the god’s greeting, especially considering her fellow True Royal didn’t even react. Instead, she sent Vesperia a telepathic message.

“Sister, I must warn you. This Minaga is no simple figure, but a being known as the All-God Legion. He was originally a Unique Lifeform with the ability to perfectly clone himself, and he kept this ability even in godhood. Making him an enemy would be ill-advised—not just for you personally, but the entire Endless Empire. Tread with caution and try to not anger him. He is known to be highly unpredictable, and he insisted on meeting you.”

“I am not aware of this Minaga figure, but I shall heed your words,” Vesperia answered telepathically. “Any idea why he wanted to see me?”

“Likely related to the Chosen of the Malefic Viper, but he never answered directly.”

“Hey, while I know telepathy is pretty fast, it is still pretty obvious you two are talking secretly behind my back, which is honestly quite hurtful,” the Unique Lifeform known as the All-God Legion complained.

“I apologize; I was merely not aware of your identity,” Vesperia apologized with a bow. “I am Vesperia, also known as the sole True Royal of the Vespernat Lineage.”

“Yep, I heard. Quite the happening to have a True Royal reappear like that.” Minaga nodded as he studied her closely for a few seconds before scratching his cheek. “Hard to see the resemblance.”

“Pardon?” Vesperia asked, confused.

“With Jake. Well, I guess you maybe have kind of the same eyes? No, not really… Hm…” Minaga stretched his neck to look at her from other angles. “Ah, never mind... I found it.”

The powerful aura of a god descended upon the hall. Vesperia frowned but remained standing like normal as Minaga grinned from ear to ear. “There we have it, indeed.”

“May I ask why you thought such tests were necessary?” Vesperia said, very unsure of what this odd god wanted. “And how are you related to my sire? As far as I am aware, he is at Nevermore.”

Minaga nodded with a big grin. “Oh, yeah, he is in there right now. Can’t say more than that, as I am not allowed to give out information like that, and that old, grouchy dragon would probably toss me out of his dungeon if I broke that rule, so definitely not worth it. Ah, but I did talk to him quite a bit. Interesting chap, for sure.”

“He is indeed a peculiar figure,” Vesperia said, nodding back with a smile.

“Right?” Minaga said happily as he looked at the Odonstrom Hive Queen. “Would it be fine if I stick around in the area for a while? Just looking to make friends.”

“We would be happy to welcome you, Lord Minaga,” her fellow True Royal said with a nod, though Vesperia could see she wasn’t overly happy about it. Yet she also knew that should she say no, the god would likely just stay anyway.

“He does not strike me as that dangerous... just odd,” Vesperia sent to the Odonstrom True Royal.

“The All-God Legion has been evaluated to possess a threat level roughly equal to a Primordial. While each version of him may not reach the peaks of power, he is, as cliché as it sounds, legion. We are utterly incapable of ending him, and should he choose to make us an enemy, we will enter a war of attrition that will only end when he gets bored or we reach a truce… and he is known to be both petty and vindictive, making both of those unlikely.”

“And you guys were worried that floor was going to be a disaster.” Jake grinned as they walked into the in-between room.

“Well, excuse me for not realizing you could just act like an entitled customer and get your way,” the Sword Saint said in jest.

“The most important thing is that it worked and was not even that high in risk,” Dina said. “If they’d been unable to feel Blessings, we would just have done the floor normally. And I think the loss of points on this floor is worth it to move on quickly, as it seems to only be increasing.”

Jake was about to agree when they were flooded with notifications.

Bonus Objective Completed: Get the attention of the clergy of the Peerin Kingdom. 500 Nevermore Points earned.

Forty-fifth floor completed. 4500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete floor forty-five by enlisting the help of the Starcrossed Twins to take down the grand barrier. 5000 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete floor forty-five within one week (7 days). 2500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete floor forty-five without killing a single member of the clergy. 1500 Nevermore Points earned.

Achievement earned: Complete floor forty-five without causing any damage to or breaking any divine laws of the Peerin Kingdom. 3000 Nevermore Points earned.

Jake chuckled. “You were saying?”

“That is…” the Sword Saint began.

“Ridiculously dumb,” the Fallen King said.

17,000 Nevermore Points—the most of any floor thus far in Nevermore—from one floor that had taken them fifteen minutes to do.

Yeah, that was definitely balanced.

Chapter 78

"I Still Got It"

Nevermore was a place where the publicly available information was far from scarce, yet there were still some unknowns.

Nobody knew exactly how many floors there even were in the C-grade version—or perhaps those who did couldn’t or wouldn’t tell—meaning for most of the individuals fighting for spots on the Leaderboards, it was just assumed they would never hit a limit. At least, not a limit of floors.

The only limits they would hit were their own abilities and the fifty-year duration. Many had tried to circumvent the time limit through the ages, but it was upheld by one simple design choice:

It just counted the age of your Truesoul using dungeon fuckery.

This meant that should one enter Nevermore in C-grade, be in there for ten years, and then leave again, the time wouldn’t stop ticking for the Leaderboard positions.

Now, this is where one truly had to separate the early C-grades that all entered below level 210 and aimed for positions on the Leaderboards, and those who were simply in C-grade and did the mega-dungeon at whatever level or pace they so desired.

The people that aimed for the Leaderboards would do best if they spent all of their time within Nevermore, never leaving for fifty years. For the people that didn’t care about the Leaderboards, they truly had no reason to stay the entire duration in one go.

It was also widely known that only the top few percent of the Leaderboards would get any rewards. This meant many gave up after realizing they were falling too far behind and just left Nevermore for a time to do something else.

The total time one could stay in Nevermore remained the same, but every second spent outside of the dungeon was a year wasted when it came to competing on the Leaderboards. To those who didn’t care, it didn’t matter. They could be in Nevermore for ten years, leave for twenty, and then do the remaining forty years if they so desired.

If someone competing on the Leaderboards did that, tackling Nevermore for ten years and leaving for twenty, they would only have twenty more years to rack up Nevermore Points when they returned. After that, they would still have twenty more years to just do floors, gain levels, do Challenge Dungeons, and whatnot, but they would have already had their final Leaderboards evaluation.

One couldn’t cheat with time dilation either, even if they wanted. You couldn’t enter Nevermore, do ten years, and then leave for another ten years in Realtime, where you actually spent two hundred years in a time chamber. The cutoff was based on your own personal time, not Realtime or Nevermore’s time.

In many ways, the most important thing for those aiming for high spots on the Leaderboards was time. Optimizing time meant more floors could be done. Of course, in order to do more floors, one also needed the power to actually complete them, even as things got more dangerous. Naturally, the levels one gained doing the lower floors would also help one go further, meaning leveling speed was also considered semi-important.

However, one oft-forgotten power on the scale of importance was the ability to cheese stuff. The ability to totally ruin how a floor was supposed to proceed, to the advantage of the Nevermore attendees.

Jake’s party was in a very unique situation, for they had everything—especially the ability to cheese stuff, which they happily used whenever they could—and they were all eager to proceed after doing floor forty-five faster than any floor prior.

The city floor after floor forty-five was quite a bustling place, but Jake and company quickly moved through after checking the Leaderboards, where they saw they had once more lost the top spot but were only a few thousand points behind the point leader.

Proceeding to floor forty-six, they found themselves on yet another open-ended floor taking place on a large planet. However, this time there was no lesson to be found, and their job was as simple as could be: Slay the Four Beast Kings—powerful C-grade beasts that each ruled a part of the planet. To do this, they would enlist the help of the large kingdom they’d initially spawned within, with a bonus objective pushing them towards enlisting in the military and influencing them to mobilize and take down the Beast Kings.

This was the long solution.

Jake and company picked the fast one.

They split up into two groups, and each headed toward a territory ruled by a Beast King. These territories were filled with countless beasts serving their king, and many powerful ones served as mini-bosses that aimed to impede them on their paths toward the lair of the Beast Kings. All four Beast Kings were apparently in the process of consuming powerful treasures that were the source of their powers and didn’t wish to be disturbed.

They got disturbed.

Group one consisted of Dina, the Sword Saint, and the Fallen King, while Sylphie and Jake acted as the second group. The power between the two groups turned out to be rather equal, and not just because of Jake, who was particularly well-suited against high-level beasts, but because of the little hawk with him. She was the highest-leveled one in their group, after all.

Besides, if Jake and Sylphie did end up needing help, Jake could always summon the Fallen King using his mask.

Ultimately, that didn’t turn out to be necessary. At least, not for the first Beast King.

After taking out a few annoying pests that tried to get in their way, they finally made it to the lair of the first Beast King on their list. Despite being the northern part of the planet, the place was a huge, mud-filled swamp as far as the eye could see, and within a small crevice was what looked like a meteorite with a massive beast lying right next to it.

[Beast King of the North – lvl 290]

The Beast King looked a bit like a hippo but had six legs and parts of its body covered in scales. It was half-submerged, with only its back above the surface, forcing Jake to strain his eyes to see its full form beneath the muddy water. It looked to be more than eight meters long and was bulky as hell.

It hadn’t noticed them, and Sylphie seemed excited to attack when Jake stopped her. “Sylphie… I have been waiting for a chance like this for over a year,” he said in a serious tone. “Please… let me have this one.”

The hawk looked at him for a moment before nodding solemnly, understanding his pain.

Jake smiled. “Thank you.”

He and Sylphie were floating far up in the air, and when Jake got permission, they flew even further up. They went above several layers of clouds before Jake stopped, feeling the mana in the air begin to act up, as they were getting too close to what he assumed was the system version of the stratosphere.

A stable platform of arcane mana appeared below his feet as he held out his hand. A thin string of conceptual energy gathered, forming the faint outline of an arrow, and a stable film of arcane energy soon surrounded it.

When everything was as it should be, he hardened the stable energy further and picked his poison. Because Jake wasn’t going to pour destructive arcane energy into the second layer of this Protean Arrow this time… He was going to pour in pure poison.

Considering the size of the beast, using the Sleeping Night wasn’t a good idea, and he didn’t wanna test any of his curse-aligned poisons, so he went with some good old Necrotic Poison. That seemed to always get the job done against flesh-and-blood lifeforms when all else failed.

After that, he carefully finished the arrow, even adding in a bit of his familiarity with this kind of beast. While it wasn’t as good as if he’d actually studied the beast, some things were generally applicable for all mammal-looking monsters.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked as she looked at the finished arrow.

“Yeah, it’s a real beauty,” Jake said, smiling. It was more than a meter and a half long and looked like a mix of black and purple due to the sheer quantity of poison within it. Something Jake had learned a while ago was that his blood did indeed count as a “form of energy” he could pour into the Protean Arrow, and he was getting close to becoming able to use crafted poison, too.

Alas, for now, he would just have to give the final product a good coating. A coating of even more Necrotic Poison.

Jake stood there with the arrow floating in front of him, carefully observing the Beast King. He felt the conceptual energy slowly build up as he found a weak spot without any scales on the back of the hippo monster. As for what was building up? It was naturally his Hunting Momentum.

It wasn’t much, but it was honest work and definitely worth pouring in.

“Now, let’s see what this bad boy can do.” Jake smiled as he took the arrow. He had poured more than ten percent of his mana and just over twenty percent of his total stamina into this one arrow. He had high expectations.

Nocking the arrow, he took a deep breath and unleashed his energy.

Arcane Awakening jumped to 60% immediately, his perception of time slowing down as he pulled back the string, and his body exploded with power from a mix of Arcane Awakening and Arcane Powershot.

Sylphie added distance as the area of over a dozen meters around Jake took on a pink-purple hue, energy crackling in the air. Arcane Powershot charged slowly as the energy built up within both Jake and his bow. After ten seconds, the crackling in his surroundings became stronger, space itself slightly distorting around him.

At fifteen seconds, he felt the energies begin to reach their zenith. He knew that his arm and shoulder would soon give out. It was time.

In a massive explosion of arcane energy, he loosed the arrow.

Jake faintly felt something in his arm snap the moment he released the arrow. It fell limply to his side, but he only gritted his teeth from the pain as he focused his attention solely on the descending arrow.

The air itself in the arrow’s way was torn apart by a trail of pure destruction, leaving a vacuum of energy in its wake as it flew with ever-increasing speed down towards the still-unsuspecting hippo. It was an arrow that encapsulated everything he had.

Arcane Awakening.

Arcane Powershot.

Big Game Hunter.

Superior Stealth Attack.

Hunter’s Mark.

Along with his passive Archery bonus, the bonus from his bow, and of course, his newly obtained Arcane Supremacy to boost everything even further. All poured into a single arrow.

Protean Arrow of Avaricious Horizons.

Soon, the arrow broke through the final cloud layer, scattering the entire cloud in the process. This finally made those on the ground aware of what was coming.

The Beast King’s eyes opened wide… but Jake wasn’t going to give it any help.

Gaze of the Apex Hunter.

It froze physically, but a torrent of muddy water still flew up to block the impending arrow. The Beast King barely had time to create a small barrier before the arrow pierced straight through, assisted by Unblemished Arrows.

The final defense of the Beast King was broken, and it had just barely regained movement when the arrow struck right between two large plates of scales. It pierced straight through the tough hide of the hippo-like beast and exploded the entire swamp, sending water splashing up several kilometers and forming a crater from the impact.

From this far up, Jake couldn’t hear the roar of pain, but he could imagine it… Moreover, he felt the response from his Hunter’s Mark.

Absolutely massive damage.

Yet the beast wasn’t entirely dead.

Flinching from the pain, Jake forcefully moved his injured arm to switch hands, holding the bow in the injured arm and drawing with the still-good one. He shot down another arrow, and only a hundred meters below him, it exploded as Arcane Arrow Rain, releasing hundreds of smaller arrows.

He repeated this a few more time, making it rain.

However… before his Arcane Arrow Rain even reached the ground, he got a notification.

*You have slain [Beast King of the North – lvl 290] – Bonus experience earned for killing an enemy above your level*

*’DING!’ Class: [Arcane Hunter of Horizon’s Edge] has reached level 233 - Stat points allocated, +50 Free Points*

*’DING!’ Race: [Human (C)] has reached level 233 - Stat points allocated, +45 Free Points*

He stopped mid-draw, a wide grin forming on his lips, upon seeing his Necrotic Poison had finished the Beast King off.

I still got it.

It felt like he hadn’t done something like this in so long. Killing a boss-tier beast more than fifty levels above his own. And damn, did it feel good. He had to admit that he was afraid he wouldn’t be able to pull something like this off again as he proceeded through the grades, but it was good to see it was still an option.

Also… he was pretty damn sure he was the only one in his party who could pull something like this off. The arrow he had just released was the strongest attack any of them had performed in all of Nevermore so far, even surpassing a Glimpse of Spring from the Sword Saint by quite a margin.

Compounding passive skills was truly an overpowered approach.

Wanting to go down and check the result of his attack, Jake used a mental command to make all the arrows falling toward the ground explode, as there was no need to cause further destruction.

Flying down with Sylphie in tow, he quickly reached the ground and saw the fallout. The Beast King had a hole more than one and a half meters in diameter through its back, with a massive crater formed right beneath it. Well, he estimated the hole to have been about one and a half meters on impact… because by now, it was far larger, as the flesh had rotted around it.

The entire beast gave off a powerful energy of pure death from the sheer potency and dose of Necrotic Poison. It was as dead as dead could be, with a look of indignation in its eyes. Its kingly reign had been ended before it could even realize what had truly happened.

“Ree?” Sylphie asked as she looked at the corpse.

“Yeah, it was a good opponent for me,” Jake said, smiling. Slow, unaware, relatively unprotected, weak to his poison, high level—thus, a lot of bonuses counted—and he’d even gotten a massive damage bonus due to the distance… Yep, the circumstances had been borderline perfect.

“Ree.”

“Only if the next Beast King survives my initial attack… If not, you can have fun with the other beasts in the territory.”

“Ree…”

“I know they aren’t as fun, but hey, you can always hope the next Beast King is a lot more durable or maybe able to dodge the arrow,” Jake said, trying to comfort the sad bird. “Who knows? Maybe it will survive my attack and put up a good fight even while injured, in which case you can have it all by yourself.”

Spoiler warning:

It didn’t put up a good fight after the first shot.

Chapter 79

Sacrifice & Dedication

Jake and Sylphie won the race to kill two Beast Kings before Dina, the Fallen King, and the Sword Saint. Their victory wasn’t by a little, either, but by more than two weeks, giving them plenty of time to mess around and catch up with the three others. The Unique Lifeform complained about them being faster at crossing large distances, which Jake just saw as a bad excuse.

After killing all four Beast Kings, they had expected the floor to be over, and if not, then for some Beast Emperor or something to spawn for them to fight. None of that happened. Instead, the kingdom they could have potentially allied with teleported over an army with the aim of taking down their party, with the reasoning that a group of five capable of killing all four Beast Kings was too dangerous for the kingdom’s political stability.

In summary, the insecure king was afraid they would create trouble, and he’d hoped that after defeating the final Beast King, they would be hurt or tired. A silly hope, indeed.

Jake was all ready for a fight, but the Sword Saint annoyingly talked down the general of the kingdom and reached an agreement. Jake and company would leave the planet while spinning a lie to the populace that they’d actually been hired by the kingdom to defeat the Beast Kings, giving all the credit for the feat to the kingdom and king.

It was all bullshit, and Jake would have preferred to just blast the bastards for trying to backstab them, but the old man wasn’t a fan of that solution. He talked about how the stupidity of a leader should not lead to the death of the average soldier, and that they would get nothing out of slaughtering an army of innocents just for a slight born out of insecurities and fear.

After they had negotiated with the kingdom, they got a group of space mages to help them teleport off the planet and thus floor using one of the treasures hoarded by a Beast King. Once they arrived in the in-between room, Jake voiced his dissatisfaction, only to get a semi-scolding, semi-explanation from the Sword Saint.

“Think about it from their perspective. Five people of immense power arrive on their planet and instantly volunteer to take down the four Beast Kings that have caused trouble for the kingdom for centuries. Within two months, they then proceed to kill every single Beast King within their lairs, all while refusing to engage or involve the kingdom in any way. We are complete unknowns in their eyes and could, in many ways, be worse than the Beast Kings. At least the Beast Kings stuck to their own territories, while we have no such inclinations. What would happen if we decided we wanted to take control? What could they do against us? No, from their point of view, striking us while we were still weak from a fight with a Beast King would be their final hope of retaining their own autonomy against five overlords taking over the only world they have ever known.”

Jake did have to admit that the old man made sense… He just didn’t like backstabbing assholes, no matter how they wanted to justify it.

“Their assumptions were shit,” Jake shot back. “We had done nothing to provoke them, nor even once mentioned we wanted to take over anything. In fact, I am pretty sure we said we were just going to kill the four Beast Kings and then move on. Can you argue they didn’t trust us and reached their own dumb conclusions? Sure thing, but what am I gonna do with that? Rather than me asking them, they should ask us first to clarify what we actually wanted to do.”

“When one party is in a higher position of power, it is difficult to approach them and ask their intent in such a straightforward manner,” the old man said, sighing. “We are in a unique position—not just as people on a floor in Nevermore, but in the multiverse as a whole.”

“So, you think we should clarify with anyone who comes to kill us whether they are at least doing it under the right pretenses before fighting back and potentially hurting them? Oh, geez, I guess I fucked up when I killed two of Ell’Hakan’s goons when they first invaded Earth. Should have asked them if they were super sure they wanted to fight first, I guess.”

The Sword Saint shook his head. “Now you are just being hyperbolic. Each situation is unique and should be evaluated with such uniqueness in mind.”

Jake was about to say more when the Fallen King cut in.

“I thought we were done with the floors about morals and norms?” he said in a mocking tone. “And as far as I am concerned, any aggressor is fair game. You may argue they have their reasons, but they also had a choice. While it is true the regular soldier had little choice, there is always some level of choice. If you claim they didn’t truly have any choice, then what choice did these Beast Kings have? What choice did the beasts guarding their territories have? For you never argued the innocence of the beasts you slaughtered on your way to the Beast Kings, nor tried to negotiate with them.”

“I can admit that my view is flawed, and I inherently treat the enlightened races differently than beasts or monsters,” the Sword Saint said. “You are right in pointing out the hypocrisy… but I still think that should there be a chance to choose diplomacy over violence. It is worth the attempt.” He sighed. “Do you disagree with that assessment?”

“No, I am saying that it doesn’t matter either way to me. Spare, kill; I am only here for the Nevermore Points. Nothing more, nothing less. So I will do whatever entails earning the most points. Things are no different outside of here, either. Whichever choice brings the most benefit with the least demerits is the one I will choose.”

“But how will you determi—” the Sword Saint began.

“Ree,” Sylphie interrupted.

“I think it is—”

“Ree.”

“Bu—”

“Ree.”

The old man stood defeated before the small hawk looking at him with annoyance. Truly, Sylphie did have the best philosophy that one could never argue with. A creature of perfect diplomacy that would forever choose the best option in any situation through her ultimate sage advice:

“Just follow the wind. The wind never likes the baddies.”

Truly, words rivaling the wisdom of the First Sage himself.

“To change the topic… I do wonder where the loot went,” the Fallen King said. “After floor forty, it just disappeared without any prompt or warning.”

“I think you were meditating when we talked about it, but Dina had a theory,” Jake said, nodding to the dryad.

“Right.” Dina nodded, having stayed out of their discussion earlier. “There are certain laws of balances, and it is possible the system won’t give out any more loot after a certain point. It is also possible this was done to combat flooding the market of C-grades with equipment. On many of the floors, you can still gather some raw materials if you want, and it wouldn’t strike me as odd if there were even characters on some of these floors capable of crafting things. Even if they can’t, there is no lack of crafters spread out across the city floors.”

The Unique Lifeform nodded. “I see. That does logically make sense, though I still believe rewards should be given for completing each floor. Outside of Nevermore Points, that is.”

Jake grinned. “I definitely agree with that.” More loot was always better, and not getting any sucked.

Alright, it wasn’t entirely accurate to say they didn’t get any loot. As Dina said, there was stuff to obtain on the floors; it just didn’t come in nice boxes. On floor forty-six, as an example, the Fallen King had taken one of the unique treasures, while Dina had taken another she could use. There wasn’t any equipment or new weapons lying around, true, but there were raw materials and natural treasures here and there, though they were a lot scarcer than on a “real” planet.

“Too much of a good thing can ruin the market…” Dina pointed out.

“It’s okay as long as I am the one with the most good things,” Jake said, grinning to lighten the mood.

The old man just shook his head, and the Fallen King solemnly nodded. Sylphie even gave a screech in approval.

Anyway, they didn’t actually know why they didn’t get any loot, but there was probably a reason, right?

Not wasting any more time with philosophical debates or talks about how much loot they did or didn’t deserve, they dove back into the dungeon. Even if they didn’t agree on everything, they were still professionals who could put aside personal feelings to achieve the best results.

There was still a long time to go, and many dungeons floors before they hit the cap for floor difficulty they could manage… and once they did hit this cap, it was time to do some Challenge Dungeons.

Carmen really wasn’t a fan of these damn morality floors, or whatever the fuck that big space lizard decided to call them. Floor forty-one had been a bloody nightmare—not just because of how creepy the place had been, but because she’d been more than a little salty after floor forty.

The Minaga fight was something she had been looking forward to… but that shit had turned out to be way more difficult than any one of them had expected. Ultimately, they had weak links in their group, and that had bitten them in the ass during the phase where they were all split up.

Warlord Davion and the druid in the party were both bloody excellent and had come out of their one-on-one fights way faster than she had. The problems were the seer and shaman. The shaman had managed to hold on but was too injured to really be of much use for the final phase, and the seer had gotten her ass kicked out nearly instantly when she was alone. She had already been pretty fucking useless in Minaga’s Labyrinth due to his interference with divination magic, but in the fight, she had just been deadweight. Worse than deadweight… She had actually hurt them by being in the party. Her magic didn’t do shit to Minaga, as she mainly did mental magic and illusions, neither of which worked on the Unique Lifeform. So her only contributions to the fight were losing them points and forcing them to constantly protect her in the first phase.

It only helped slightly to learn that at least that guy Casper and the Risen had also failed to do the Minaga fight without losing someone. It had helped a bit more to learn that the Holy Church had lost three members, including that Bertram guy, who’d ended up taking down the Minaga with some insane suicide attack that ended phase three just as it began. Ah, but it was sad to hear that Caleb’s group hadn’t even been able to face Minaga properly, just another damn Demon Lord with a clone of Minaga only there to occasionally fling in spells to make it harder. The same appeared to have happened to Maria and her party.

From what she had learned, the only parties that had done the Minaga fight without any losses—of the people she knew or had heard of, that is—were the odd ones, or the ones she had really expected to do it. One of them was naturally Jake and his ridiculous party, which was really expected, while another was that weird scientist guy named Arnold, who Gudrun had warned her about not making an enemy for some reason. Carmen wasn’t sure why, as the guy didn’t seem that dangerous on the surface, but then again, the quiet ones did tend to be the ones you didn’t wanna fuck with.

Besides that, Eron had also succeeded with his group of monks. It did suck to hear that bastard Ell’Hakan, who had attacked their planet, had also completed the fight flawlessly, based on the intel one of Valhal’s agents told them during a briefing on the city floor. To see her party members celebrate him had been a bit hard to swallow, but she kept her mouth shut to not stir the pot and reveal anything she shouldn’t.

It had been extra hard to keep things under wraps once her party developed more interest in her and her origins after the Minaga floor… mainly because of the ridiculous intel on her fellow Earthlings, which had led to quite a few questions and subtle probes.

“Your planet is odd,” Davion had said to her in an attempt to break the ice on the subject while they were flying on a barge, right after arriving on what they later discovered was a bloody plague-themed floor. This was his first time bringing up the subject directly, and Carmen got the vibe that he wasn’t going to hold back.

“Yep,” she just agreed.

“The Unique Lifeform, I understand, is originally from a tutorial, so that is explained… The Sylphian Hawk also seems related to the Malefic One’s Chosen’s special ability to influence monster Origins. That Judge is also easily explained, as he is the brother of the Malefic Viper’s Chosen, so that could just be a case of nepotism. However, that does not explain all the other outliers. A transcendent swordsman, a Risen with enough talent to be recognized by the Blightfather, another individual with an odd Bloodline now part of the Dao Sect, an Augur of Hope. Then there is that enigmatic man who entered a pact with a Void God yet remains human. This isn’t even mentioning you. It just all seems highly unlikely for so many talents to appear on the same planet at once.” Davion was really voicing the thoughts of everyone in the group. Well, besides maybe the ranger that had joined them after floor forty to replace that bloody useless seer. Carmen hadn’t really had time to talk to that gal much yet.

“I agree,” Carmen said, nodding.

“You don’t question it?” Davion raised an eyebrow.

“Nope.”

“Most would. Do you not see problems in the future when too many powerful forces gain an interest in your planet? A curiosity like that will attract attention whether you like it or not.”

“Oh, sure, I see a bunch of problems for Earth. That doesn’t mean they are my problems. Valhal is in a pretty bad position there already due to the planet pretty much belonging to the Chosen of the Malefic Viper now, and I guess they are just waiting to toss us out or something.” She had to play a little into that lie where the Order and Valhal were actually in a conflict, right?

“That is true, I suppose. Though I thought you had a good personal relationship with the Chosen of the Malefic One already? Or at least some of his party members?”

“I guess I do.” She shrugged. No use in keeping that a secret after their constant meetings back on that Minaga city floor. “I knew him before this entire conflict, after all, and we are definitely still friendly. Ah, but I do have the go-ahead from the higher-ups.”

Yeah, Carmen was bad at this.

“I see,” Davion said, nodding as he sighed. “A bit of a shame that even someone of your position will have to make such personal sacrifices, but one must do what is expected. We are still C-grades and subject to the wills of the higher-ups if we wish to remain with Valhal. Alas, I am sure your dedication will be honored. The Chosen’s unique ability is simply too invaluable to give up on, it seems.”

“What are you talking about?” Carmen asked with genuine confusion.

“You have been tasked with trying to seduce and get close to the Chosen to bring him over to our side, right?” Davion said without a hint of jest. “That is why you kept meeting with him despite the conflict. That is what I have deduced, anyway.”

Wait, what the fuck?

Carmen was about to curse at him, but she stopped herself. This could… work?

“Yeah, you got me.” Carmen sighed in an exaggerated matter. “But keep it under wraps, okay? Now that you know, you must help me make sure no one else suspects I have a personal relationship with the Chosen before it is time to strike. This is a highly secret mission coming directly from Valdemar and Gudrun themselves.”

Davion’s eyes opened wide as he nodded seriously. “I shall do my utmost. I honor your sacrifice and dedication, Runemaiden.”